Hi this is John Sonmez from Pluralsight and welcome to this module on querying and Hibernate.
So far we've learned how to map data and to use those mappings to put data into our database using Hibernate.
But what good is getting data into a database if we can't get it out?
Just like we can use SQL to query a relational database directly,
we can use Hibernate to query the database in terms of the java objects we've mapped.
In this module, we'll go through the basic features of the Hibernate querying API's
and learn how to create queries for getting back data from our my SQL database.
Just like we could using SQL natively.
We'll also learn how to use the eclipse Hibernate tools to enable us to test our queries in an editor
to quickly get feedback and check results.