Now one common thing that you might want to do is to take all of these queries out of your code.
It can be a little bit messy to have HQL inside of your code.
You might want to have this in a separate place where you have all your queries
and then you can just call your queries by name.
This can be done pretty easily in Hibernate.
For example, we can take our from GoalAlert and we'll just take this out,
we'll put this into our GoalAlert configuration.
So under hibernate-mapping we can add query.
We can give this query a name. Let's see, AllGoalAlerts.
And then we can actually put our query in here.
And usually we want to put this in a CDATA tag
just to make sure that it doesn't get parsed by the XML parser and get interpreted as XML data.
So we can do that by just adding CDATA, and then we'll put our query in here,
and then close this tag.
So now we have our query. It's a named query called AllGoalAlert.
And we can use this from inside of our code by calling on session get name query.
So we can say session.getNamedQuery' and we can specify what our query name is
which was AllGoalAlerts, so let's go ahead and put that in here.
And you can see that this actually returns us back a query
so we can actually use this in place of our query.
And now we're getting all goal alerts.
So we can go ahead and run this and we should see all of them show up.
And now we can look at our results and you can see we've got everything coming back:
Good job! You made it! Taco time! and Yes!!