Now one thing that you often need to do in SQL, and you'll also need to do in HQL, is to be able to do joins.
Joins in HQL are actually pretty easy, for the most part.
In fact we get a lot of the join functionality for free.
You may have already guessed that when we created our query like this where we said
'where user.protienData.total' is greater than zero.
If we run this it actually will be doing a join for us.
We get back all of our users, because we set protein for all of them,
but if we go to this Hibernate Dynamic SQL Preview, let's take a look and see what happened here.
Well, you can see that it's already done a join for us because remember this protein data lives in another table.
So we got what is called an implicit join.
Hibernate figured out the in order to get the protein data and check the total on it
it would need to join against the ProteinData table.
So we're selecting from protein data users, and then we're joining to protein data,
and then we are implementing our where clause.
And we're also restricting the join, making this an inner join,
by restricting it so that this id matches up from the protein data to the users.
So in many cases you don't actually need to explicitly have a join in your HQL.
You can basically just reference something that is part of another entity
and it will automatically do a join if needed.
Now you do have to be careful here because you might not be getting the most optimal join.
Now the best thing to do is to look and see what SQL will get generated for your HQL so you can determine that.
Often times you can just go one level and not have a problem
but if you start going a couple of levels you might want to think about changing this and using an explicit join,
which I'll show you next.