Now it's pretty likely at some point that you might want to do an explicit join.
You may want to do this because you want to optimize the query,
because you want to control how the join is being done.
We could rewrite this join, that's implicitly being done, to be an explicit join
simply by using join here.
And then we're going to say 'join user.proteinData', we can name this table as pd.
Remember we don't actually need this as. We could take this out in both places.
And then we can simply do 'pd.total' is greater than zero.
So if we run this you'll notice we get back our three results.
And if we look at our SQL preview this looks pretty much like it did before
we're just explicitly saying that we're going to do this join.
We could also join unrelated tables. We don't use the join keyword to do that.
We basically just select from both of those tables and then manually create a link between them.
So for example let's say that we wanted to select from user and goalAlert.
Remember goalAlert is mapped through that other table so it's not going to explicitly be mapped.
But in our case we do have goalAlert mapping to a user but goalAlert doesn't know anything about user.
So if we said GoalAlert ga, then we're going to actually be getting form both of those tables,
you're going to already see this query changing.
And then let's take out the join and we're going to say 'where user.id' equals
and we could do 'ga.', and it's not going to make sense to join an id because these are unrelated pieces of data,
but we could do this there's nothing that would stop us from doing that.
So we would basically be joining ga and user table, the GoalAlert and User table,
and you can see the SQL that it generate here that actually generates this join
and then it uses this where to basically restrict this.
And if we run this we're going to get some results and that's just simple because we happen to have
the same number id's in our GoalAlert as we do User.
So it does give us results.
But this kind of join is definitely a much more rare case.
In fact most of the time you can get away with the implicit join
and I only really use the explicit joins when I know that I need to control how that query is being generated.
I'll look at the SQL first and then decide that I can do a little bit better job by doing an explicit join.