Now there's quite a bit more you can do with HQL,
we've covered all of the basics but you can do things that you can do in SQL.
Like subselects and group bys and havings, pretty much all of the functionality of SQL, you can find in HQL.
But like I said, we've covered all of the basics except for one thing that I want to show you now
that's a unique feature of HQL that I find really useful and not too many people know about.
But if you do know about this, this is going to save you a lot of time of having to cast objects,
and pull data out, and extract them when you can have that being done for you directly in the query.
So I've set up a scenario here, what I've done is I've created this class called UserTotal.
And this class basically just has a name and a total.
And in the constructor we can take in a name and a total.
And it's just a way to get just the users name and the total and not have anything else.
You could think of this as something that you might bind to a user interface element,
perhaps, if you're using something like MVVM or MVC.
And you wanted to use some kind of object that you're going to bind your user interface
you might create something like this, where you just need the names and the totals.
In that case, what you would normally have to do, is in your code, you'd have to create query
that gets the user, and then takes out the name, and then takes out the total,
and then loops through all that data and constructs a series of these UserTotal objects.
But what I've done here I've set this up so that we can do a dynamic instantiation of this class.
So you'll notice in my createQuery I have a select and then I'm using this new keyword,
just like we would do a new in java, and I'm specifying the full name of this class.
So I'm doing new UserTotal, it's com.simpleprogrammer.UserTotal.
And then I'm calling the constructor, just like you'd call the constructor of a class,
except I'm using the path to the data that I want.
So for example, I'm getting user.name and I'm getting user.protienData.total
and then you can see I'm just doing this from User and I've aliased this to user.
Now you have to get his exactly right, you're not going to get autocomplete on this,
so it can make it a little bit difficult.
But if you do this what will happen is this query will actually instantiate UserTotal
and instead of returning us back users, like it was before, or alerts when we had it set up for alerts,
it's going to actually return us back a list of these UserTotal objects,
or a collection of these UserTotal objects.
And you can see here that I've set this up to receive this back this list of UserTotal.
And we're going to go ahead and loop through all of the userTotals,
and we're going to go ahead and print out the name followed by a colon, and then the total.
So let's go ahead and run this code.
And you can see form our console output that we get Joe: 50, Bob: 20, Amy: 200.
So I thought that's a pretty neat feature that everyone should know about
because I've written a lot of code here, where if I were jut getting the user
I'd have to loop through all the users and then create new user total
for every single user in that loop.
And that's just a lot of wasted code when you can have Hibernate do that for you automatically
directly in your query.