Let's test out the criteria API by using the criteria editor in our eclipse tools.
So we're going to go to Hibernate perspective.
Then I'm going to go to this Hibernate tab.
From here what, we can do is, we can do the same thing that we did before
so for example, if I want to query this user data, I can go to this Hibernate Criteria Editor
and you can see by default it generate a criteria query.
So the basic way that we create a criteria query
is that we use session.createCriteria and then we can pass the class
that we want to create a criteria query for.
So in this case we're using User.class.
If I were to just run this, you can see that we get back all of the user objects.
We don't have any restrictions on here.
This is the same thing as doing a select except that we're doing this in a more object oriented way.
Notice we don't have any string that contains a query; instead we're using a blank criteria for a user,
which is going to match everything.
And unfortunately for the criteria editor, we can't see the SQL that's going to be generated.
If we go to this Hibernate Dynamic SQL Preview, you'll see that it says No HQL Query editor.
So we can't actually see what's going to be generated. In this case, we have to actually run it to find out.