Now you probably don't want to just do a query that returns you back all users or all of some entity.
You probably want to have the equivalent of a where clause, in HQL or SQL,
and we can do that with a criteria API call as well.
The way that we do this is we just chain an add-on here.
So after we call create a criteria, we get back a criteria object,
we can all add on it to make another criteria object that now has this restriction added.
So we're just going to do '.add(Restrictions.' and then here you can see all the options
you can basically do any kind of restriction you can think of, it pretty much has everything here.
We're just going to use a simple equal.
And we're just going to check that the name field is going to equal to Joe.
So we can go ahead and run that and you can see we get back one object, and it's Joe.
We can chain another restriction on here, which will act as an and.
So if I do restriction, dot, equal, and I do id is equal to one.
That's going to and that and we get back Joe again.
And if we wanted to we could do an or.
So this is going to be an and automatically because it's going to add all these restrictions
but we could add an or by doing '.add(Restrictions.or' and then we can specify whatever we want in this or.
So we could say restrictions, dot, equal, and we could do name Joe.
Or we could do restrictions, dot, equal, so then we can do name Bob.
And so this will match either on Joe or Bob.
And we'll go ahead and end this with our two end parenthesis, and then a semicolon.
And if we run this you'll notice that we get back two results.
We get back Joe and Bob.
So you can build up all kinds of complex restrictions using this.
It is going to be a little bit verbose, as you can see here,
but this is nice because you can programmatically add these.
So in your code, for example, you could basically have different restrictions that you add.
You could say if some condition then add this, otherwise don't.
Which a lot easier than if you were trying to construct some HQL
where you're trying to create sting and you have to worry about commas,
and you have to worry about whether or not you're at the end of the list or not.
Here, you can just add as many restrictions or criteria that you want.