So another useful thing for criteria is the ability to use projections.
Now this is going to be equivalent to, basically, the select part of an HQL or SQL query
except this is going to come at the end.
So the easiest way to do this is to call setProjection and then we're going to use a projection.
So we can do Projections, dot, and you can see there's all kinds of things
like distinct, we've got rowCount, average count, and max, min.
But we're just going to do something simple; we're going to do property,
and we're just going to do the id property.
So this will just give us the id, it's like saying select id.
So if we run this you can see we get the id's 1 and 2.
Now we can also add more than one projections by doing setProjection and then we can use Projection list.
So if we do Projections.projectionList, this gives us a projection list which we can add projections to,
so we can add projections, dot, and then here we can do our property, and we could put for example, name,
and then we could chain this again and do add projections, dot, property id,
then we'll close this.
And if we run this criteria you can see we get Joe and Bob.
Now normally we would get back id, we're just not seeing it in this tool
because it doesn't show us the secondary projections.
If we were to switch this order we would see id and not name
but we are getting both of these back if we were to actually run this in our application.
Let's go ahead and look at this in some code.
I went ahead an took this criteria query that we created,
I put it into our program so you can see it right here with our projections.
And then what I'm doing is I'm calling list and notice what comes back here
we actually get an array of objects.
And then I'm going to loop through these array of objects,
and then I'm going to loop through each object in that array.
And so what we should expect are these two properties, the id and the name.
We're only going to get back one result in this case
so when we print this our we should see the ID followed by the name.
Let's go ahead and run this.
And now if you look at the console output you can see that we're getting 1 and then Joe.
So when you do use these projections, you will have to deal with an object array
unless you map this to some other object like we had done with the HQL queries earlier.