So now's a good time to talk about joins with the criteria API.
It doesn't quite work the same way that HQL does.
So for example you might think that you might be able to do something like this.
If we did a projection and then we said property
it seems like you should be able to do proteinData.total.
After all, you could do that with HQL.
But if we try to run this you'll notice that we get an error.
And it basically can't resolve this proteinData.
So the reason why it can't do this is because we actually have to manually specify the join,
and we do this with an alias.
So we can say createAlias.
And then here we need to specify this proteinData property off of our user,
and then we're going to actually call this pd.
So now we can reference this with pd.total
and we've told the criteria that it needs to include this table for this proteinData,
and it will allow us to query off of that.
So let's go ahead and run this now and you can see we get 50 and 20 because we're getting the pd.total.