There are actually a few options for querying in Hibernate that we can choose from
and often you'll find that combing these different methods of querying by using the strengths of each,
where it is best suited, is often the best approach.
Our first option is to use the HQL or JPA QL API's.
These API's allow us to query Hibernate using a syntax that's very similar to SQL.
It's so similar that you might not even realize that there's any difference than regular SQL
unless you look closely.
In this course we'll be covering HQL as HQL and JPA QL are very similar
but since HQL is Hibernate specific and JPA QL will work with any JPA compatible ORM.
By learning HQL, you'll be pretty close to learning JPA QL as well.
And since we are using the Hibernate API's already, and not JPA,
there really isn't any advantage in using JPA QL.
The second option, which we'll also cover in this module, is to use the Hibernate criteria API.
This API is a much more object-oriented approach to querying Hibernate
but it makes it much easier to programmatically write queries, as we'll discuss a little later.
Finally, we can use the Hibernate API's to execute in native SQL
but we won't be covering this querying option in this module since this is more of a special case
and not a recommended approach.
We will talk about native SQL in the next module, though, because occasionally it will be useful.