So let's take a quick look at an example of query by example.
So we're just going to go ahead and create our example object first.
We'll create a user and we'll just do a new user.
And then we'll populate this user with some data.
We're just going to set the name so we'll just do user.setName.
And we're actually going to set this to lower case Joe, and you'll see why in a minute here.
And then we're going to need to create this example object, we're just going to call it e.
And then we do example, dot, create, and then we pass in what we want to use as an example.
So we're going to use user as an example.
Now we can actually change some things to this example. So I could do ignoreCase, for instance.
You can see all these different things like enableLike, so we could use the fields as if they were likes
So something similar to Joe would match.
We can do ignoreCase, which we're going to add.
We actually add all kinds of different things to this to make it so that we control how this example is matched.
In our case, let's just do the simple case of ignoreCase.
And then now we'll cerate our criteria.
We'll just do session.createCriteria and we're just going to do User.class.
And then we can do our .add here.
So if we do .add and add e it's going to add this example to our criteria.
Now if we just run this you can see we get back one object, which is our Joe
and it matched even thought we had a lower case Joe
So we could also do anything else we want with this criteria.
We can add restrictions, we can set our projections, we can do anything else that we can do
because this is just a standard criteria.
We could even add more examples if we wanted to build up some criteria.
Now this is really useful because what this allows you to do
is to simplify your code greatly when you're trying create some conditional matching.
So if you can imagine if you had some kind of a screen where you could flip all kinds of options,
or maybe you had an advanced search in your application,
you could basically use that populate an object and then use that as an example.
And then your criteria is automatically going to be created.
If you think about writing the HQL to do that you'd have a lot of if statements,
and even if you tried to use the criteria API without the query by example,
then you would still have to write quite a bit of code.
But here you can do something very simple, anytime you have an example object you can use that to do your query.