Hibernate query language or HQL is really easy to learn and understand if you're already familiar with SQL.
HQL queries are written with a very similar syntax to regular SQL
except that they are operating against the java objects you have mapped instead of SQL tables directly.
As you'll see when we talk about joins in HQL, this actually gives you some extra power
of being able to reference related entities in an HQL statement and not having to do an explicit join
like you would with a traditional SQL statement.
There is, however, a major weakness of HQL to be aware of.
Just like it can be difficult to programmatically construct SQL statements,
it can be difficult to programmatically construct HQL statements.
So you'll probably find HQL works best in situations where you'll have a mostly static query
that will differ in parameters passed to that query and not how it's constructed.