So the first thing that we're going to do is to create some sample data to work with.
I went ahead an already created some sample data for us, I created this new method called PopulateSampleData.
And we're going to go ahead and get rid of this other code that we had
since we're not going to be using this anymore.
We're just going to, basically, populate some sample data and then we'll close our session factory.
And if you look at this PopulateSampleData, all that I'm doing is I'm basically getting our session open,
beginning a transaction, and I'm creating three users: Joe, Bob, and Amy.
We're saving all those, committing that transaction.
And I created this very simple method to help us to create users quickly,
just so that we could add some test data.
It basically just creates a new user, adds some history to that user,
and then also adds any alerts that we pass in.
So this will give us some basic data to get started with.
We'll go ahead and run this against our database.
And you can see that everything ran correctly. We did quite a few inserts and updates in there.
And now let's open up MySQL Workbench
and let's just take a quick look at this data that in the database.
So if we refresh this, I went ahead and cleared out all of our old data,
so we just have our tables that we created here.
We're going to start with the users table.
If I look in here, you can see we have Job, Bob, and Amy.
We have ID as 1, 2, and 3. Then they're associated with these PROTEIN_DATA_ID's
We can follow this and look at the proteindata table
and here we've got the protein data for each one of those users; the totals and the goals that I set.
And then we can take a look at the user goal alert in the goalalert, this is the mapping.
Remember that, when we look at our structure here, we don't have any reference from users
we're using this mapping table.
So if we look at user_goalalert,
we've got a user id that's mapped to a goal alert.
So you can see, for example, USER_ID 1 has GOALALERT's 1 and 2. 2 has 3. 3 has 4.
So if we look at goalalert, we can see here that we have 1 and 2 that went to our user 1, or Joe.
We've got 3 and 4 which correspond to the other users.
So that gives us some data to work with.
We're going to be querying this data from this database now that we have a little bit more information
in our database than we did with our previous example.