So we're actually going to be doing most of our querying when we learn about HQL
inside eclipse using the HQL editor.
We'll go ahead and add some code a little bit later on to test out the HQL in our actual application,
but we want to be able to quickly execute HQL and change it and not have to write code to do that.
So an easy way to do that is just to use this HQL editor.
So in order tot get this working, what we'll want to do is we'll want to go to this Hibernate view.
And if you don't have a Hibernate tab showing up here you can go and add this
by going to Window and then Show View, and there should be the Hibernate view here.
And let's just expand this a little bit so you can see that Hibernate Configurations.
And then we already created this Hibernate Configuration in the first module.
There's a reason why we set it up this way and that's so that we could easily be able to use this HQL editor.
So if you haven't set it up this way, if you've just created that config file,
you will want to create this Hibernate Configuration.
So you can see here that it gives us out Configuration, our objects here or classes.
And then we have in our SessionFactory we have these same instances.
Now a quick way to just do a query is you can look at any of these entities in here,
for example, User, and if you right-click, you can go directly to HQL Editor.
And it'll bring up the editor and it will just do a simple select statement.
So that's a good way to get started.
You can also just click this HQL, here, and it will bring up a HQL editor as well.
So once we have our HQL Editor open, we can actually run this.
And you can see this is just an example of some HQL, here.
We're just using 'select user from User as user'
with HQL we don't actually need this select user.
With JPA QL we actually do so there's a slight difference there.
I typically just use the select because it looks a little bit strange to me to just see this.
So let's go ahead and run this.
All we have to do is click this run button.
And then it's going to return us back our results in this Hibernate Query Result window.
Here you can see something that's now very useful. You're basically getting the object IDs
That's not going to be very useful to us but if you take a look at the properties, over here,
you'll notice that we get some additional information.
Let go ahead and make this so we can see this a little better.
So right now in properties we're seeing some information about our particular query.
So we've got our query string, we've got the tab name, the query size, how long it took to run,
but if I click on one of these objects then you'll notice that it actually gives me this little object explorer,
here, where I can see the identifier, I can see the properties, and I can actually expand through this
and look at the data. Including the goalAlerts, the history data,
I can go through here and look at the protein data.
So we get some pretty good ability to explore our objects from here.
And I can click on any one of these and see, this is just what's coming back from this HQL results.
So this tool is pretty useful for creating queries and exploring those results.
The other thing we can do with this HQL Editor, is you see I've created this HQL statement here,
but if I go to this HQL Dynamic SQL Preview, it's going to basically give me a preview
of what this is going to generate as far as SQL goes.
Because remember, Hibernate isn't doing this by magic, it's actually generating SQL to do a query
or to do updates and inserts, everything that we're doing.
It's basically a query.
So if we look at this you can see that this is a little bit hard to read
but it's some SQL that came out from this.
Which is that we're doing this select, we've got our columns names, here, id name, and then protein data.
And then we're selecting from protein_tracker.USERS.
Now without going too far off topic I do want to point out something here,
because it is a good time to look at this, which is you'll notice that we're getting this ID,
we're getting the NAME, and we're getting PROTIEN_DATA_ID.
We're not actually getting the protein data. We're not doing a join here.
And that's because Hibernate is smart in that it doesn't do joins and get all the data,
it doesn't fetch it aggressively. It basically does like a lazy loading.
So for example, e when we actually click on one of these properties, so if we click on proteinData,
it's actually going to do a fetch there and grab that data, it doesn't have it in the initial result set.
Which is a good thing because especially if you had a very big result set
you wouldn't want to get all of that data at once.
So that's a basic HQL Editor that we're going to be using.
And you've also seen the basic select statement.