Let's take a little bit of a closer look at our select statement.
As I said before we don't actually need the select user part, we can take this out if we want to.
You can leave it in if you think it's a little bit more clear.
I do prefer to leave it in in most cases.
But we can just use from User, and we actually don't need this as.
What we're doing here with this user is we're basically aliasing this table so that we could use this later on.
Well the as is optional.
But we also don't need this user because we're not actually using this anywhere else in the query.
So we could actual reduce our query to just from User.
And you can see if I run this that we still get the same results.
Now let's go ahead and see how we would actually use this in a program.
So we're going to go to our application and let's go ahead and get a session.
So after we populate the sample data we'll get our session.
And we're going to do session.beginTransaction,
and then we're going to do this session.getTransaction at the end, and commit.
Now if you're just doing a query you really might not need a transaction,
we're just going to put everything in a transaction just to be safe, make sure no data's changing.
It's just a good habit to be in.
So then the next thing we're going to do is we're going to create our query.
So we're going to use a query object, you'll need to import that.
We're going to call this Query, and we're going to basically just do a session.createQuery
and then we put in our query. Which remember is just from User.
That's going to give us our query.
To execute our query, the easiest way is to just call list.
And this is going to return us a list of users.
So we can make a list of user and then we can call this users.
Then we're going to set this equal to query.list.
And this is of course not going to return us back the typed list of users
so we're just going to assume that this is the list of users because we know that it will be.
And then we can loop through this.
Let's just go ahead and loop, we're going to say user out of users.
And then in this loop let's just do a System.out.println and let's just print the name.
We'll just do user.getName.
So this will prove that we get our list of users. Then we're doing a commit on our transaction.
We want to close our Session Factory but we also want to close our session.
So we'll do session.close.
So we'll go ahead and save this and let's give this a run.
And one thing that you might see here, if you noticed that this hung for a little bit here,
is that you may need to go over to your Hibernate Configuration, here.
So remember we were in our HQL and we'd run this query.
Well it tends to hang on a session and so if you have that problem
what you'll need to do is just to go over, here, and the if you right-click
and then you just say either Close Configuration or you can do a Rebuild Configuration.
And what it will do is it will, basically, let go of that session that was open and then your code can execute.
So now if we look at the results of this, you can see we have Joe, Bob, and Amy.
So that's now we execute our query in Hibernate.
We basically just create our query with session.createQuery
and then we can execute it with list.