Now for most of the time you're probably not going to want to get all of the user entities.
You're probably going to want to do some kind of filtering or restriction on your query.
And we can do the same thing as we would in SQL with the where clause.
All we need to do though is add back this user part so that we have something
to work with our where clause against.
We're going to say, basically, 'where user.' and using this HQL editor it will autocomplete this for us
so we can see that we have goalAlert, history, id, name, protein data.
And you'll notice that there's this N-1 icon, here, and there's an id, and this one doesn't have anything.
This is basically telling us that if we do something like goalAlerts
we're going to run into a potential N-1 problem.
We're, basically, going to be getting another table in order to get the actual data.
So let's go ahead and set this up so we'll do our restriction just on the name.
We're going to say where user.name equals and we're going to put in here 'Joe'.
So we're just going to get users that have the name Joe.
I'll go ahead and run this.
We need to open our session factory when we first run this.
And you can see that one result comes back; just the user with the name Joe.
And we can do most of the things that you can do with SQL.
Here we can add ands, we can look at whether or not something is greater or less than something.
So we could say where user.name equals 'Joe'
and we could do user.protienData.total is greater than zero.
And we could run this and you can see that this runs as well and returns us back one result.
We get the information about that run, and we get back Joe.
And of course we could get back some specific data if we put this select back in.
We could say 'select user.' for example let's just grab his id.
And if we were to run this you can see we just get back that id.
We could actually get back some other type of object, we could get back the goalAlerts for him.
And then you could see we're getting back those two goalAlerts.
And we can even do some checks on our collections.
So for example, we could just say 'where user.goalAlerts is not empty'.
So this will get any user that actually has goalAlerts.
Which we can see that we're getting four goalAlerts.
Let's just grab the user instead of the user's goalAlerts.
So we're getting back all three users because they all have goalAlert collections that are not empty.