Now you may find that you'll want to have a parameter passed to your HQL query.
This is pretty common and you can do this in HQL pretty easily.
So for example, let's say we have 'select user from User as user'
'where user.name' and we want to specify a name. So we might want to pass this in programmatically.
We can use this :name to use a named parameter.
And all we have to do is fill this in, in our query.
So we can actually do this inside of this HQL editor
if we go to this parameters here, you can see that I've already added a parameter
and I've filled in the value of Joe.
You just hit this plus parameter button and it will go ahead and detect the parameter that's in your query
and you can just put in a value there.
Once you've done that, if you run this now you can see we get just one result,
we're just getting back Joe.
So this is how you can test this out inside of the HQL Editor
but you probably want to actually run this in some code as well.
So to run this in code, all you have to do, is you can I've already filled this out,
I already have our query in here.
So we're just going to use our query. We're going to put our colon name inside of there
and then I'm calling this setString.
I'm actually just using some method chaining after createQuery I can just do '.setString'
and we could actually chain whatever parameters we had.
So maybe we had a bullion parameter or whatever else we had we can just add set and then the parameter name.
We can even use objects.
There's a setParameter that's sort of a generic version of setParameter that will let you set anything
and we can even set an object.
So for example, we could query based on matching a user.
Instead of looking for user name we could just look to see if a user matches some user object that we created.
But let's keep things simple and just run it like this, and we should expect that we're just going to get Joe.
Now I have had some problems with this query editor.
It does seem like if you open the query editor, even sometimes when you do this rebuild,
or do this close configuration, it doesn't seem to let go of this session factory.
So I've found that I do have to sometimes close out eclipse and then come back in.
So I'm just going to do that real quick and then we'll take a look at running our actual application.
Okay, so now I'm back here in eclipse and we're going to go ahead and try and run our program.
So we're just going to go ahead and run this.
And let's take a look at our output and you can see, after everything's happened, we just got back Joe.
Because we were able to filters on the name where name was equal to Joe,
and we passed in this name programmatically using setString.
So that's how you use the name parameter.
We can also use numerical parameters or positional parameters like you can in JDPC SQL queries.
But I'd recommend against that because it's just not a very good practice
because if you change your query around you could end up messing up the order of those
and things can definitely break.
When you use the name parameter you're going to be sure that it doesn't matter what order this comes
so for example if you added an and clause, maybe you said if 'user.id' equals and you put id and,
it's not going to mess things up whereas you use positional parameters, it will.