Now one thing that we can do very easily with HQL is to implement paging.
This is a very common problem needing to be able to page data or get just a subset of some data
that you can page through like pages in your application.
For example, if you have a web application and maybe you have a little arrow
and you're showing ten results at a time, this is sometimes a difficult problem to solve.
But we can do this pretty easily in Hibernate, so let's go ahead, and change this
so we're going to get rid of our where clause.
We're just going to select all the users, in fact, let's go ahead and change this so that we just get the alerts.
Because these alerts, if we look at our alerts, there are more of them in here,
so it will make more sense to page on this.
So let's say 'from GoalAlert' and we currently have four GoalAlerts in here.
And what we're going to do is we're going to say set '.FirstResult'
So we can say let's start at result number two and then we can also set the max result.
So we could say '.setMaxResults', and we could set this to one.
So we could basically go one at a time if we wanted to.
So let's go ahead and try this out. We'll just change this here from user to GoalAlert.
And we'll change this to alerts,
and then alert and GoalAlert.
And then we'll just print out here what that message is.
So we'll do 'alert.getMessage'.
Let's go ahead and run this, and now you can see that we got this one message of 'Taco time!'
Which was, basically, the second result in our result set but we only got one back.
If we were to take these off and just run this,
you'll see that we get back the full set, we won't be paging this at all.
So we get back everything: You made it! Good job! Taco time! Yes!!
And so we can use this to basically do paging.
So you can imagine you can pass a variable into here and you could set the first result
to be whatever you wanted and this could be your page size.
Maybe you're returning ten results at a time and you're on page zero, page one, page two, and so forth.