Well by now you might be wondering well what good is it to be able to store our data inside of our database
if we can't get it out? So now were going to go ahead and just see a very simple way to retrieve our
date out, it's going to use that same mapping in order to do basically the reverse of what we've done so far,
we've basically taken a Java object and we've generated some SQL to do an insert to basically insert that
Java objects into Hibernate. But we can take things the other way and go ahead and take that object from
our relational database and create a Java object from it. So what were going to do here, is we're basically
going to create a new transaction which were going to after we've saved our data load our data back out.
So I'm going to go ahead and leave this in the same session, because there's really no need to create a new
session. But I am going to create another transaction so I'm just going to say session.begintransaction.
And then remember we always want this session.commit at the end or roll back so let's do a
session.gettransaction, and then were going to do commit, and then we'll put our code in between this.
So inside here what were actually going to do is session.get and then were going to specify what were going
to get out. So the basic way of using get is that we're going to specify the class, so we're going to say
user.class, and then were going to specify the id so let's just do an id of one.
And then we should be able to get back our user, so we'll say loaded user.
And you'll notice that get doesn't know he type so we need to add this cast to user and you'll notice there's
not really an overload that's going to let us do this in a generic way unfortunately.
And those things would be a little bit easier, but it's simple to cast this since we know what the type is.
So now that we have our user we can go ahead and print out some information to make sure we got the right user.
So let's just do a system.out.printline and we'll go ahead and printloadeduser.getname, and then on the
next line lets go ahead and do loadeduser.get and we'll say get the goal.
I'll go ahead and save this, we'll run this and now if we take a look at this output you can see what's
happened here is we've done our insert, and then were able to do our load, you can see that we get Joe
and 250 back. Now besides using get, you can also use load, so we could change this to load.
There's not much of a difference between get and load, if you use load and you specify an id that doesn't
exist what will happen is that you'll get and exception, if you use get you'll get back null.
So let's go ahead and run this again, and this time were using load we get the same result.