Now Hibernate is also automatically able to detect if you've changed and object that you've gotten from
Hibernate, it keeps track of what's occurred on that object. So for example if we take our loaded user,
we're going to print out our name and goal, but after this if we said loadeduser.settotal and we set this
equal to loadeduser.gettotal plus let's say 50, then what will happen is when we do this commit it's
automatically going to do an update on the user and update this user.
So let's go ahead and run this, and if we look at this output here you can see we get Joe we get 250,
and then Hibernate automatically did an update for us. So if we go to out My SQL to check this out you can
see here, let's go ahead and select from here that the total was set.
So this is really useful, this basically means that when you're using Hibernate you can basically load
objects out of Hibernate and then you can manipulate those objects and then when you commit the transaction
it's automatically going to persist those changes to those objects.
Because those objects are basically being managed by a proxy, that Hibernate creates that's able to detect
when a change has been made to one of those objects.