Mapping in Hibernate can be done in one of two ways, we can either use XML files to specify how Java
classes should be mapped to your relational tables, or we can use annotations in our code to create the
mapping. We'll mainly be focused on the XML route because it is more widely used, and doesn't require us
to add Hibernate data to our Java classes, we won't have to persist using Hibernate.
When we map Java classes to relational tables we can use POJO's our Plain Old Java Objects.
This means that we don't have to inherit from any special class, or do anything unusual to make it so our
classes can be mapped with Hibernate. The only real requirement for a Java class to be persisted with
Hibernate is that it has to have at least a parameter list constructor.
You don't even need getters and setters, or even need to make the fields public, but it's probably a good
idea to create getters and setters on a Java class you're using in persistence.
Once we have our Java class we can create a mapping file that will specify what table the Java class will
map to in our database, and also what the different fields we want to persist will map to.
For much of the configuration file we can omit this information as long as the names of the columns in the
database match the names of the fields in the Java class, but we can also be specific if we need to.
The final piece of mapping is of course to have a database table that matches what is specified in the
mapping file. We can either manually create this table, or we can use the hbm2dll.auto option, which
we'll talk about a little later to create the table automatically.
Once we have these three pieces, we can create Java objects and tell Hibernate to save them and it will use
the information in the mapping file to generate SQL, which will persist our object.