It may have occurred to you that Java types don't exactly match up with the SQL types perfectly.
Fortunately Hibernate has a pretty easy solution for this problem by having its own mapping types.
Here you can see a table that has some of the common Hibernate mapping types, as well as a corresponding
Java types and SQL types. This table isn't a complete list of all the types, but it should give you a
general idea of how things work. Hibernate is pretty good at figuring out what type of field in our Java
classes without us having to specify it in the mapping file, it uses reflection to do this.
But we can also be specific and tell Hibernate what type the data should represent.
When we do that we use one of these Hibernate types here on the left most column.
Hibernate knows that a Hibernate mapping type should correspond to a Java type specified in the second
column, and a SQL type specified in this third column. This means that Hibernate can automatically do the
proper conversions and generate the proper SQL to make it so you don't have to worry about converting Java
types into compatible SQL types yourself.