There are a couple of different ways of course that you can use Hibernate in an application, some developers
will prefer to create the entities or the classes inside of their Java project first, and then to generate
the tables or create the tables in their database that correspond to the classes and their application.
Other developers for a variety of reasons, especially if you're working with legacy code where you might
already have a database and tables will do the opposite and they'll have their tables declared first, and
then create Java objects that mirror those tables. For our example were going to go ahead and start from
inside of our Java project. So what I'm going to do here, is I'm going to create a class and were going to
call this class user. This is going to represent a single user in our protein tracking application.
So this user is going to contain some data about the protein that it's tracking for that particular day.
And what its goal is, and then as well as an id and a name, some pretty simple data, but it will work for
the purpose that were going to be using it for.
So let's go ahead and click finish, and then inside of this user class what I'm going to do is I'm going to
give this user an id, so I'm going to do a private int id, and then I'm going to give the user a name, we'll
say private string name, and then we'll say private int total, so this will represent there total protein
count. And then we'll do a private int goal that will represent their goal.
Then I'm going to go ahead and hit control 1 on each one of these to generate a getter and setter.
(typing)
So now we have getters and setters, we basically have our class that were going to use on the Java side.
I'll go ahead and Save this, and you'll notice here that we haven't done anything special, this class is just
a POJO or Plain Old Java Object, there is nothing really special about it, it just has some fields and it has
some public getters and setters.