Now that we have our Java class for our users we need to create a table to store the users in, because
remember we actually want to store the users inside of our My SQL database.
So I've opened My SQL workbench, I'm going to go ahead and go to my local instance, type in my password for
route, then inside here we have our protein tracker schema. You'll notice that we don't have any tables, but
we can right click here, click Create Table, and you can just generate the SQL for this yourself if you want
to, but if find this tool to be pretty useful. So I'm going to go ahead and call this users, I'm calling
this users plural, that's usually the convention that I use. And then were going to add some columns, so the
first column we need an id, by default it give us id users I like to call mine id, since we already know
this is the users table. It is set as the primary key, it is set to be not null, so we can have a null
value there. Then we need to add the name, so we'll make the name. Instead of Varchar 45 let's go ahead
and make this 100, that should be big enough for a name. We'll make it so this is not null as well.
And then we need to have our total, and we should probably make this an integer, and not null.
But we can make a default value of 0, and then finally we need a goal, so let's go ahead and put our goal,
and we'll make this an integer as well. And then this should be not null, we can put the default value of
let's say 100 here if it's not specified. Make sure we get rid of this extra column that it created for us.
And now we have everything we need for our table, notice that this matches our data from our class, now we
happen to use the same names here, which is going to make our mapping easier.
But I will show you how you can deal with if you have a different column name.
It is defiantly best though if you can use the same column names, as you have in your Java class because its
going to make things a lot easier, and they're going to make a lot more sense, it will just be easy to figure
out what column things map to. Let's go ahead and click apply, you can see it generates this DDL for us.
That basically will create that table, ill click apply and now it's finished running that, and if we look
we have a table user, but it doesn't have any data in there if we select from there.
So now we have our table, we have our Java class, the last thing we need to do is to create our mapping file.