Now the next thing that we need to do is to create our mapping file, and we'll need this to actually be
able to map this user class we created to that table we created in our My SQL database.
Were actually going to cheat to do this, we can do this in a little bit of a simpler way, were going to go
to our Hibernate perspective, and from here what I'm going to do is inside this com.simpleprogrammer I'm just
going to go to New, and I'm going to select New xml mapping file.
Then you'll notice that it basically asked me to add classes and packages to create and empty mapping file.
Let's go ahead and remove that package and we'll go ahead and add a class called user, you can just do a
search for user. And you should see user come up, then I'll go ahead and click Finish.
And you can see that it's created this user.hbm.xml file. Now if we take a look at this you'll notice that
these tools give us a way to view this in a pretty nice way, as well as the original configuration that
we created. Well we can see some things like the id, the name, the total, in the goal, and you can go ahead
and take a look at this. This is a good way to get familiar with the mapping tool, because it has a lot of
the information that you can set on here. But we can also look at the source, and if you don't have this
tool installed if you're doing this manually, you can just create this XML file.
It's not that complicated, it is important that you understand this though, rather than just relying on this
tool. So let's take a quick look at what was created here. So first we have our doc type, just like we
had our doc type for our Hibernate configuration. This basically is going to specify what's valid inside
of this mapping file, then we have this Hibernate mapping element, everything has to be inside here.
And then the first thing that you'll notice is this class, so class, we'll have a name which will be our Java
class name. And this will be fully qualified so its com.simpleprogramer.user and then were going to map
it to a particular table, now this table is set to user, but that not quite right because our table is
called users, so let's go ahead and make that change. So then next we have id, in id we'll have a name,
this name is going to correspond to what this is in our Java class.
So we have an id field in our Java class, the type this is our Hibernate type which is int.
And then we have a column specification, so in our table this will be the id column.
And this generator class is set equal to assigned. Now with generator we have a few different options,
generator is basically going to determine how this id is generated.
There is a few different options here, if I go ahead and auto complete this you can see there is assigned,
foreign, guid, hilo, identity, increment, native, select, quite a few different choices here.
And it really is going to depend on your database, and also have you have things setup.
We can actually set this if we want to, to increment, which will just automatically increment this by
manually picking the highest number. We could also set this to be identity, if we set this on identity, we
do need to make sure that the increment is on our database itself.
So if we go back to our SQL workbench, we can go to our users table and I'll go ahead and do alter table,
and for this id column we need to make sure that auto increment is set.
So go ahead and apply that, so now that this will auto increment. And you can play around with a few
different ways to use a generator, it's really going to depend on your application on your database technology.
so I can't give some general guidance here, but were going to just go ahead and use identity for now, and then
you might want to research what is the best choice for whatever database technology you're using.
So this is basically going to define the column that represents our id, this will be our unique identifier
for a particular user. Then we have all the rest of the properties with these property elements.
So it works almost the same way, we have property, and then we have the name, so our name for name is name.
Were specifying the type here, which is Java.lang.string, and then we have the column names applied in this
column element, which is name. And since these are going to be the same we actually don't need this, and
you'll also notice especially if you're manually creating this xml file, that you can basically just use
column here and specify it. This column element is really usually used when you have a lot more specific
stuff that you need for that particular column. We're not going to get into those details because we're
going to keep things pretty simple, but in many cases you could even get away with a mapping that looked
something like this, and that would work because Hibernate is able to figure out the type and everything
from your Java class. Now the problem with mapping things like this is that there will be some hit because
it will have to do reflection to figure this out. If you tell Hibernate like is done here by this generated
file, then it's going to reduce that hit, it's going to be a little bit faster.
So it's up to you if you want to keep things simple, it really doesn't take a lot of effort to add the type
and the column name. So I usually do that in my mapping, but again there's a lot of different reasons for
arguing one way or the other, it's really up to you. We next have our total, same thing here and then our
goal. So that's our basic mapping file, and we do have to do one last thing in order to be able to use this
mapping file. Let's go ahead and Save this and were going to go to our configuration, so let's go back into
our configuration. And for mappings we need to go ahead and click Add, and then I'm going to go to Browse,
and then were going to look inside here and look for that user.hbm.
Our configuration needs to know where all our mapping files are in order to be able to user them.
So you can see here now if I go to the source it's basically just added this mapping element that says that
it's a resource.