Well now comes the moment of truth where we get to find out if our mapping, our Java
class, and our SQL database table are all in sync. Don't be surprised if you've got something out of sync
and it doesn't work properly the first time. Many times when I create mappings I scratch my head trying
to figure out what exactly is named slightly incorrect, or where my problem is.
So it shouldn't be a big shock if you end up having problems. Now I will help you out in a little bit here
and show you a way to avoid some of these problems, but let's look at this manual process first and see if
what we got works, and if there's anything we need to do to adjust this.
So we have in our program created our session, were using this get session factory, were opening our session,
and then were just doing session.close. We should also probably put in here a close for our session factory.
So let's do Hibernate utilities.getsessionfactory.close. And then in between here were actually going to do
our work. Now remember that we want to do things inside of a transaction, so let's go ahead and do
session.begintransaction. And then were going to end this by closing our transaction, so I'm just going to go
ahead and do a session.gettransaction, which will get the current transaction, and then .commit.
And were going to put our actual code inside here, so what were going to do is just create a user.
We'll just go to user, we'll do a new user, and let's set some date on this user, we'll say user.setname.
We'll set the name to Joe, we'll do user.setgoal, we'll set his goal to let's say 250.
And then were not actually going to set the total, were just going to let that default to 0.
And I'm going to call session.save to go ahead and save this user.
Now this should serialize our user to the database if we don't have any problems.
So let's go ahead and run this, and we'll test this out and see what happens.
So let's look at our console output and see what we get here. So were seeing two errors about this could
not bind factory to JNDI, you may recognize this, we have this error parsing JNDI name.
And it's actually the same error here as well, so this is actually coming from, remember that in this
particular version of the tools it doesn't quite match up with our newest version of Hibernate, so this is
actually invalid. So we can go ahead and save that and if we were to run this again, we can go ahead and run
this again and we'll add another entry there. You can see that both of those errors should disappear, and it
looks like everything has worked, and were actually seeing the SQL that it used to do the inserts.
So this looks proper, let's go ahead and look at our My SQL workbench, so I'm just going to go ahead and
startup My SQL workbench.
And then were going to go to our local instance, put in our password.
Now we'll go to protein tracker, tables, or users table, I'm just going to select rows, and you can see that
we actually have two pieces of data in there. So our first entry did work, and our second one did as well.
And again if you have a problem remember there is quite a few different moving pieces, you do have to make
sure that your column names are going to match up to what you have in your mapping file.
If we go to our mapping file, here you got to make sure that these things are going to match up all these
column names. And then also your Java class fields need to match up in here, so it's really easy to get
something wrong, or to have a problem. And again with the generator we happened to use identity because
we have the auto increment. You will have to figure out for your particular database if you not using My
SQL what is going to work the best? And then again if we had a different column name, so let's take a look
let's suppose that maybe we had instead of name we used something like username, or some other name for this
column. All we would have to do is change it here so that this column name said whatever that column name
was. And again we could remove all of this, and things would still work.
So let's go ahead and try that just to demonstrate this. I'm going to go ahead and Save, we'll run again.
And you can see that we don't get any errors, so looks like everything worked, and if we go and look inside
of our database, we'll go ahead and select, you can see that it did insert a third row.
We'll go ahead and revert this back though, because like I said I do prefer to have this explicitly mapped
in here, it does save a little bit of time on not having to do that reflection, but again it's up to you to choose.