Now can be fairly tedious to need to need to create new database tables for all the Java classes you want to
persist using Hibernate. Especially when you're developing new features and Java classes that don't already
exist in your database. Hibernate has a built in feature that can be used at development time, that can
make your job much easier. In our Hibernate config file, we can specify an hbm2dll.auto option.
Which allow for auto generation of the ddl, ddl is just some SQL that generates schema for our database.
Like creating tables, or views, ddl stands for Data Definition Language.
When we turn on this option, we can have Hibernate read the mapping file, and use the data in the mapping
file, to automatically create tables for our objects so we don't have to manually create them ourselves.
This can save a lot of time when developing, but this feature should not be used in production because there
is no guarantee your existing data won't be harmed, and some of the options will actually wipe it out on
purpose. There are four options that hbm2dll.auto can be set to, First you can set a two validate mode,
and in this mode it won't actually make any changes to the database schema, but it will just validate that
the schema matches the mapping file. Update mode will not the existing tables, but will update them, or
add new tables when they are missing. Create will check to see if a table already exists, and drop that
table if it does along with any data in it. And then finally Create-Drop will work just like Create mode,
except that it will clean up after itself, and drop any tables it created when this session factory
is closed.