Alright so let's go ahead and give this tool a try and see what it looks like to automatically generate
our tables for us. Now before we do this, I do want to say one more time that you should not be using this
in production, this tool is really great for development it makes things a lot faster, but it is not going
to be very careful with preserving your data. If you're going to be making migrations to database tables,
and schemas in production you're defiantly going to want to use something more robust, and you're probably
going to want to either use some tool that is specifically geared toward migrations, or manually generate the
SQL for those migrations, because you want to be careful to preserve that data.
So before we do this lets go back into our workbench, and what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead
and drop this users table, I'm just going to say drop table here.
So now if we look inside protein tracker we don't have any tables, if I do a refresh all, you can see there's
nothing in here. Let's go ahead and close these query windows, and now we'll go back to our project.
And what were going to do inside here is we're going to go back to our Hibernate config, and you can of
course manually edit the xml, but we might as well use this tool.
We're going to properties, were going to go under Hibernate, and then you'll notice that there is this
hmb2ddl auto, if you click the arrow you can see that there are the four options that we had talked about.
We're going to use create, which is basically going to drop any tables that exist and recreate them.
The only difference between this like we said in the Create and Drop is that the Create-Drop cleans up after
itself, whereas this will basically do the cleanup before it runs.
So were going to go ahead and set that, I'll Save this. Then were just going to go to our main program and
all were going to do is run this. So I'm just going to run this, and you can see were getting our same
problem here with the naming, so let's just go ahead and fix that real quick, again when you use this tool
you're going to end up having that problem with the name, which is easy to fix.
And while were in here you can see that it basically just set this one property hbm2ddl auto.
Let's go ahead and run this again so we should actually see two rows now, and if we look at our console we
don't have any errors, so everything is looking good. You can see here though that we have some more SQL,
we have this Hibernate telling us drop table if it exists, protein tracker.users, and then it's doing this
create table, and you can see it's automatically creating this table for us switch the auto increment on our
id, and pretty much everything that we had specified earlier, and it's doing an insert.
So were going to back to My SQL workbench, I'm going to go ahead and do a refresh all, and now you can see
that there's a table called users and it's got everything that we expected in here under our columns, we've
got out id, name, total goal, and if I go ahead and just do a select from here you can see that we have
our data. So now one really useful thing that you might have figured out form this whole process is that
we can basically work inside our Java application, we can create our Java objects like we did with user,
we can basically auto generate our mapping file like we did here, and then tweak it how we did for example
we wanted to make the table called users. And then if we turn on that setting to auto generate the ddl, then
we can basically just run our application and its going to automatically generate our tables in the
database, and then we can basically do an export of this, and get the ddl that it used to create this, and
then use that for our actual applications. So this can save your quite a bit of time by automating a lot of
this process, now you might have to manually go in here and change some things and make sure that everything
is correct, but it can really save you a lot of time, especially when your first working on a project if your
spiking something out, or working on its own feature, you don't have to go in and generate all the SQL
yourself, and generate all these mapping files yourself.