Hi this is John Sonmez from Pluralsight, in this module we'll be diving into the scary Hibernate world of
mapping relationships. In any non trivial application you're going to have relationships between different
pieces of data, after all if you don't have any relationships, why even use a relational database to begin
with? Well in Java relations between pieces of data are pretty simple and fairly limited in the ways they
can be expressed. Relational databases themselves allow for a much larger number of ways to express
relational data. And when you combine this with Hibernate you get even more ways to express relations
between data. Fortunately you only need to understand and use a few basic types of relations from most
applications, so we don't have to all be experts in mapping relationships.
In this module I'll take you through some of the most common types of relationship mappings you're likely
to want to do with Hibernate, and show you a few of the less common ones as well.