Okay so now the last thing we need to do is to map this, so let's go into our user
mapping, and what were going to do is we're going to map this as a set, we can use this set that's built into
the Hibernate mapping we set the name and this is going to be our field, which in our user class is called
history. Then inside set we can set a few different things, first of all we want to tell set what the table
should be, that it will use. So were going to have it use a table called user history.
Then we need to specify what the key is for that table so we're going to say key column and we're going to set
this equal to id, now the reason why were using id here is because we're going to have for the key for this
user history table be the same id as our user id. And the reason why were doing this is because remember
this is a value type, it doesn't exist on its own were just using this as a foreign key to the users table
so that were essentially mapping this user data to this user history data, it's basically going to create
this one too many we can have multiple user histories for a particular user and its going to create that
relationship. Then we just basically add our composite so were actually going to use composite element.
We need to specify what the class is for user history so were going to say com.simpleprogrammer.userhistory
and you do have to put that full qualification there. Then the properties just like we had done before, so
let's just say property name equals and we have entry time and let's double check that.
We've got our entry time and our entry, so we're going to put entry time and the type will be equal to date,
and you can auto complete this to see the types, you can see that we have date in there.
And then the column name lets go ahead and call this entry time, so we'll just do it like this.
And then we need another one for the actual entry itself, I'm just going to copy this, paste this here,
we'll call this entry. The type here is going to be string this time and the column would be called entry.
We'll go ahead and Save this, double check and make sure we have everything here so we still have our protein
data, now we have history that's in this set the key is going to be the id column
So let's go ahead and go back to our program and we'll run this, and we'll look at the console here, you can
see that we don't have any errors. Let's see what we've got for output here, it's created the new user
history table, we have entries it looks like that it's put in there, and then we have down here for output we
have Joe, we've got 250 and then you can see that there's a date followed by a message.
So we've got the set goal to 250 we've got the set name to Joe, so and then we did our update.
So if we look back at this code for our program you can see where we've basically added these history items,
there part of the set. When we loop through here were getting them back out so were able to store the
user data along with its history all in those two tables and then get that data back out and it's right here
for us to access off of the loaded user. Let's go ahead and open up the My SQL workbench, I'm just going to
do a refresh on this, and you can see we have a user history table. If I select from here you can see
there's three entries, with this entry time, and you can see what entries are, those three entries that we created.
And this is all for id one so if we look at our users table you can see if there's an id one, Joe his total
is 50 his goal is 250, so this set data relates to that particular user.