Now let's see how we can map a list instead of the set, to convert our example to a list won't take much
effort at all, what were going to do is go into our user, and were going to change this from a set to a
list, and from hash set to an Array list and of course remember a set is basically going to not have an order,
but is going to allow at most one of a unique thing inside of it.
Whereas a list can have any number of elements in there and they can be duplicates if you want, but there
going to be in a specific order. So let's go ahead and do our imports.
And then we'll need to change our getters and setters. Instead of set we'll be using list here we'll be
a list. And pretty much everything else will remain the same our program still makes sense to add items
to our list. And then we just need to update this mapping, so the only real difference here is that were
just going to change this from set to list, and we need to specify one other thing, remember a list is
ordered so it needs to have a column that's going to specify the order, so what were going to do is were
going to use this list index and inside here we can specify the column name to use to store the order.
So let's just make a column called position, and now what will happen is that on our user history table it
should add this position column, which will have the position or the ordering of the items in this list.
So were going to go to our main program, we'll go ahead and run this now.
Let's take a look at this output real quick, there really shouldn't be much of a difference here.
If we look we've got Joe 250 we've got the two items that were in that list in order and then we did our
update and added our third item afterwards, so if we go to My SQL workbench and we refresh this tables and
then we go to user history. Let's go ahead and select from here, you can see that we now have our entries,
but we have position one and two so it's keeping track of the position in there, so that it will be able to
bring that back as an ordered list for us. And then if we look at our users table we can see that we have
our user. So everything is almost exactly the same, the only difference really here is that we could have
duplicates if we want to use a list, and we have this position or basically this index list, index column
that we could call whatever we want.