Now that we've seen how to map a set and a list, let's see how we can map an actual map.
So this is not going to be very difficult either, were just going to convert this over to a map and what
we'll do in this case is we'll make it so that were going to have basically an entry id, we'll have some
kind of entry identifier that will be the key for this map. So let's make a map of string, user history.
And we'll set this to a hash map here, we'll do string user history, do our import, and then we'll change
our getter and setters.
And this should be string, and string over here. And then we will need to change our program because with
a map we don't use add we use put, and we need to specify what the key is going to be.
So let's just add some fictional entry id, perhaps we have some kind of entry id that we uniquely generate
whenever we add a history item. Let's just say a GL123, and then we'll just add one for this other one,
let's say its GL124. Then here in our loop, we'll need to change this, let's go ahead and make this so that
instead of get history it's also going to get the entry set. And we'll change the type here, so we have this
entry set, and then we want to actually get history.getvalue and then we can get the entry time.
We'll do the same thing here, get value, and then let's go ahead and put out that key so it will say system
out.printline and we'll print out what the key is. We'll say key value and then we'll do history.getkey.
And then we just need to fix this one last reference here, to be a put, and we'll just put like GL125.
So now we have this all set up, we just need to change our mapping.
So this is actually pretty easy were just going to go into user instead of list you can probably guess that
we're going to use map. Now maps have a key, and then they have their values, this key here remember is the
key that corresponds to this id up here, it's how we're going to identify what this history item goes to.
But we need to add a map key, so we can say map key, and then we specify the type which is a string, and
then what the column name should be, let's just call this entry identifier.
Then we can get rid of this list index, and lets go ahead and fix the slash on this, so now were all set,
that's all we need to do to map a map. We'll go ahead and run our application, and you can see from our
output, we don't have any errors, and you can see that we've got our key value of 124, and here is the actual
value that was in there. And then we've got 123, and here's the value that was in there.
Remember a map like this is not sorted, so the order is not going to be guaranteed.
If we wanted the order guaranteed we'd want a list or some kind of a sorted map.
And now if we look at our My SQL workbench, we'll just go ahead and do a refresh here.
If we look at our user history, you can see that we've got our id entry time, and tree and now we have this
entry identifier, which is basically the key for our map. And if we look at our users table we can see that
we have our user in there as well.