Now we can also map a plain collection in Hibernate using either a bag or id bag.
So what I mean by this is for example we could just do collection, and not specify set or list, or anything
like that. I'm going to go ahead and do an import, let's go ahead and convert this over.
It will actually be pretty simple to do, we do need a concrete type here or an implementation so let's go
ahead and make this in the ray list, but it doesn't really matter what were using here because it's going
to implement that collection interface. And then we'll just fix these getters and setters to use collection,
and we won't have the string part.
And then let's go back to our main program and we'll pretty much convert this back.
We'll just make this be add, and then the same thing here with our loop, we don't need to do this entry set
anymore were just going to get the history. And this will just be user history and then we won't have a key,
and we don't need to call get value. And we'll fix this last one here, just make this add.
So now we can just use this just as a collection, we need to update our mapping and what were going to use
here is we're going to use the id bag. Now we could just use a bag, basically a bag or even an id bag is
going to allow you to just have a collection of things, they can be duplicated they don't have any order.
So and the reason why were going to use id bag is because we want to make it so that we don't have to have
everything be unique. If we just use bag then really the unique identifier for the row is going to be all
of our data for that row, so we couldn't have duplicate rows in there.
But by using id bag we can have duplicate rows, it's really not that big of a deal the difference between
id bag, and bag, just in the case where you have data that you might need to be duplicated.
If you want to be on the safe side you can just always use id bag in those situations.
So were going to use id bag and the only thing we really need to do with id bag that's a little bit unique
is that we need to have a unique id. So were basically going to create a surrogate key or this unique
identifier for every row in here, which is not going to be the combination of our columns like we have by
default. So we just set this collection id and we have to specify the type in this case it will be an int.
And we have to specify the column; we'll just call this id. And then inside here we need to specify a
generator just like we did for our id up here, and were going to just set this equal to increment.
So now we have our id that's automatically going to be generated. And we were already using id for our key
column, lets actually change this to user id because that actually more accurate anyway now that we have
two pieces of data here because this is really a foreign key that going to the user table, so if we say
user id that makes a little bit more sense. And then were going to get rid of this map key, a little trick
with Hibernate mappings, see how that squiggly red line disappeared? Well that will help you to know when
you've got this mapping correct. So because we had for example if I bring that back, this map key its
incorrect that's not a valid for an id bag. So if you're missing something, or you have something extra it
will give you an error there. So now we have everything mapped, we can basically just run this.
So let's go to our main program, and we'll run this, and let's take a look at our output.
We can see that our output looks good, we are getting the output that we expected we got Joe 250, and then
we got those two entries in there. And if we go to the My SQL and we do a Refresh, we can see our user
history table and inside here now you can see that we've changed the column name here for user id, this maps
to the actual user id in the users table. But now we have this id that's going to act as a unique identifier
for this particular table so that it won't be having to use a combination of these column so we can actually
have duplicate data, whereas before we wouldn't have been able to.