The first and most basic type of relationship for entities
is one to many, if you just learn how to do this type of mapping you can handle most entity mapping
situations, since in most cases one too many will work. With one too many relationships we are mapping one
entity to 0 or more other entities. You can see this example looks just like the collection example, and
that is because on the Java side it's exactly the same. In fact on the database side it can be modeled
like a collection with the addition of a unique key to identify the entity on the many side.
There are actually several different ways to model this data on the database side, but we'll look at just a
few. We can change our history examples so that the history items are entities instead of value types to
demonstrate this. We might want to do this if we decide later on that history items needed to be refereed to
from some other entity like perhaps the entity responsible for creating the history item, or associated to it.