So let's go ahead and create the one to many mapping from our user to our user history.
So in order to do this what were going to do is we're going to change things a little bit, first of all were
going to convert this back to a list, and then let's go ahead and change the getters and setters.
And remember now were making this an entity this user history, so we're going to have to have an id and we'll
have to change a couple of things about user history. So let's go inside of user history next, and inside
the user history what were going to want to do is we're going to want to add an id, and were also going to
make this relationship go both directions. So we should be able to access the user from the user history and
access the user history from the user. Because in a case like this where we have two separate entities it
makes a lot more sense to have a backwards reference. So for example if we queried on user history, and we
got back some user histories, we'd want to be able to go back to the actual user without having to do
another query. So let's go ahead and first of all we'll create our id, so we'll do a private int id,
and then we'll do a private user. And let's go ahead and add some getters and setters for these, and
at this point we won't really need this hash code or equals override anymore since we basically have an id
and that ID is going to unique. So now we have our user history and what we'll want to do is to make it so
that when we add a user history to our user that we enforce this relationship.
We're going to want to set this user, so what were going to do inside here is we're going to add another
method. Let's add public void add history, and this is going to be the preferred way of adding something
to the history as opposed to either calling set history which we defiantly don't want to use, or calling
get history and then adding items. So here were going to take in a user history, and we'll just call this
history item. And then inside here we want to do two things, first of all we want to take our history item
and we want to say set user, and we want to set it to this. So we want to make that relationship go from
history item to user, and then we want to make sure that we add to our history item list so we'll say
history.add this new history item. So this is going to make sure that we have the relationship going both
ways, which is really important if we want this to work correctly. A lot of people that are trying to get
Hibernate working get tripped up here and they'll only add the relationship one direction and then they'll
wonder why it doesn't work, so you do have to do this, it is good to create a method on one of the classes
that will do this for you so you don't have to do this everywhere that you try to make a relationship between
two entities. Now we also want to go back into our main program and we want to change this, remember we
don't want to do this get history anymore we want to call add history so that it sets up the relationship
properly. So were just going to basically copy this in everywhere where were doing this get history we want
to change this to our add history.
And it is still okay to call the get history here because we are actually using the history in that case.