So nowt the next thing that we'll want to do is to create our mapping files, so we're going to start off by
just going to our user history and I'm just going to do new Hibernate XML mapping file, were going to select
user history, click Next, it's going to actually try and update three of these, what were going to want to
do here is we're going to make sure that it doesn't actually change user and then it doesn't add this protein
data one. If we let it do this it would do it in a way that will work, but not exactly how we want it to,
we want things to work a little bit differently. If you take the time after you've watched this module and
see how were doing it and then compare to how the generator will do it you'll see that this isn't quite the
best way to do things. So what were going to do is just generate user history, I'll go ahead and click
Finish, now we have this user history mapping we'll look at the source here.
And you can see we've got our id, so that's good the generator we wanted to make this increment just like the
other one. Then we've got this many to one mapping for user, and this is pretty close to what we want, we
don't actually need this fetch part we can replace this with a not null, because we do want to make sure
that we never have a null from our user history. If we have a user history it should always belong to a
user, so it's important to put a not null on this. And it's got the column name here as user, if we want to
we could move the column up into here, but either way will work. Also notice we've got our properties,
we've got our entry time and our entry, and these look correct as well.
And notice when the generator does this generation it actually uses the Java type, we could of course just
use date or string the Hibernate type and that would work as well. So now things will work properly from
this end our user history will reference our user, but we need to make it so our user mapping is correct as
well. Right now if we look at our user mapping you can see that were using this id bag, and we've basically
got this composite so were basically using a component because we were treating this as a value type.
Now what we want to do is first of all we've decided that were going to use a list, so let's switch this up
to be a list. And then with a list we don't need this id, so we can get rid of that.
We still want our key because this is going to map to that other table, and then we need this list index,
we'll bring this back, and we need to have a column for this so let's call this column position like we had
before. Now we don't need this composite element, instead of composite element what were going to use is
we're going to use one too many, and here we just specify the class which is going to be
com.simpleprogrammer.userhistory. And you want to make sure you get that absolutely right, and notice here
that here we've got a one to many, and if we went to our user history we have a many to one so it's the
inverse of that, but there's still an issue. If we were to use this right now there is two problems,
one we basically have two entities in the system, so Hibernate doesn't know that these things are related in
a bidirectional relationship. It treats these as two unidirectional relationships, so this means that for
example if we add a user history to our user, and then we tell the user history that it has a user, just like
if we look at that code that does that inside user, right were setting both of these relationships.
We'll be modifying to entities so when we go to save these entities it's going to basically try to update the
id that foreign key that linking these things twice, which we don't want.
So we need a way to tell Hibernate that these things are basically related to each other, that this is a
bidirectional relationship, it can't infer it automatically. So what we can do is we can set this inverse
and we can set this to true. And all this does is tell Hibernate hey when you have user and user history,
this relationship here is bidirectional so you only need to do an update on this user id once.
Since this is the key we don't need to change it twice this refers to the same thing if we change the user
id inside our user history it's going to map to the same user. And then we can get away with this, but we
can take this one step further and we can make it so that we don't have to save these entities separately.
So in fact we can test this out just to see what we'll get here I'm going to go ahead and let's just add this
to our configuration, we need to have our mapping so let's add another mapping resource, this will be our
user history. Then let's go ahead and run this just as it is and we'll see what we get.
So you can see we got some errors, we basically got this error that says object references an unsaved
transient instance, save the transient instance before flushing user history.
So what's happened here? Well if we look at our code what's happening is we are basically saving user, but
we've got history, these are two separate entities so what we actually need to do is do session.save and then
we need to save each one of these history items, so we need to store them in a separate variable, and we'd
need to save them or we'd have to access them off of user. Because remember these are two separate entities
there not values types anymore so there managed separately. But we can fix this because we can basically
say to Hibernate, hey anytime you're saving the user save all the history to, create those entities because
they belong together I want you to save everything that is off a user.
So the way that we do that is we set this cascade option, again this is another place that trips developers
up because they don't realize what this is actually doing. So what we can do is we can set this to Save and
Update. And if we do this it will make it so that when we save user it will go ahead and cascade this entry
here of the user history, so if we have new user history entities that are attached those will get saved as
well. So now if we run our code if everything went correct we should see that everything is working, so
you're seeing our correct output here, and then let's go ahead and look in the My SQL workbench, I'm going to
go ahead and refresh this and you can see actually we ended up getting a user history without the underscore
because we just had generated that and we didn't change the name so this is the one that we just created.
And inside here you can see that there's three rows, we have our position 0,1,2, we have our user set to one,
and we've got this user id set to null. We can fix that; we'll fix that in a minute because we don't
actually need this user id anymore, but let's take a look at our users table real quick.
So we can see we have our id of one, name, total goal. So if we go back to our code you can see that we've
got in our user this user id which is fine because this is the key column, but we want to make this matchup
right here when we have this many to one, we have the column name as user so if we just change this to
user id it's going to match to that column name that we had on the other side and so it won't end up creating
an extra one or duplicate. So let's go ahead and run this real quick, and now we'll take a look at our data
and everything should be right, we'll refresh this, look at our user history and here you can see that we've
got everything right, were now using the same user id column. So you do have to be careful with that as
well because it does have to map on both sides it has to match there. So that's it, it's a little bit of
effort as you can see to get this set up, but it is something that is critical to understand a lot of
developers are really confused by this many to one, and then where does the inverse and the cascade come into
effect and how do I use that? So this is the basic way to set this up to set up a true bidirectional
relationship where it will cascade from this user class to the user history.