So now let's go ahead and make it so that we have a one to one mapping for our protein data in our user.
Right now if we were to look at our user mapping you can see that protein data is a component, but we can
make protein data its own entity. So in order to do this were going to start off by going into protein
data and were going to need to add an id, so let's go ahead and do a private int id.
And then we also want to have a reference to user, so let's do private user.
We really want to set up a bidirectional relationship when we do a one to one mapping because it does
actually make things easier in that case and it doesn't really make sense to have this protein data be
orphaned by itself. You want to get back to the user from it if you were to query on protein data.
So then the next thing that we want to do is go into our user, and we need to change this a little bit.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a constructor, let's do public user.
So inside this constructor we want to setup our protein data, and the way that were going to do this is were
actually going to call set protein data and pass in a new protein data.
And then what we'll do here is we'll eliminate this, and then in our set protein data let's go ahead and go
to this, we want to set up the relationship correctly so we want to also set this up so protein data.setuser
is equal to this, just like we had done with this add history. So now were setup and ready to go ahead and
create our mapping.