Before we get started with relationships, it's important to understand a few basic concepts, first we need
to understand the difference between value types and entity types.
If you've studied DDD or Domain Driven Design, you may already be familiar with the concept, but most Java
developers don't really have to make a distinction between the two in every day Java code, so don't worry
if this is new to you. Any particular piece of data can either be expressed as a value type, or an entity
type. Let's look at an example to understand the difference; first we have the value type.
An example of a value type would be a person's leg; we would normally make this piece of data a value type
because it doesn't make much sense to exist outside of the context of a person.
Another way to put this would be that we would never reference a person's leg by itself, we'd always get this
data from a person that is associated to it, the leg doesn't stand on its own so to speak.
Next we have entity types, person itself was an entity type in our previous example, and we could easily
imagine a situation where person has a phone, the person might have ownership over the phone, but the phone
exists itself without the person and doesn't require the context of a person to make sense
We could give the phone its own id, and other entities could refer to it, it could exist on its own even if
we remove data about that person that happened to own it at the time.
So entities are basically pieces of data that stand on their own and can be referenced outside of the
context of another thing. Well value types are pieces of data that depend entirely on the entity that
references them. Value types do not exist on their own, now it is important to realize that this distinction
is self imposed. What I mean by this is that there are no hard and fast rules about what kind of data is
a value type verses which is an entity type. Instead you have to decide for your specific application and
your data how you want to treat the data. Do you need the data to stand on its own?
Or does this data belong to another piece of data, which it doesn't make sense without?
Whenever you're creating a mapping in Hibernate involving relationships it's important to make this decision.
Because it will greatly affect how the data is mapped as we'll see in a bit.