We're going to start off by generating a mapping and then we'll modify this, so were
just going to go to new XML mapping file, we've got protein data, we don't want to regenerate these other
ones so let's go ahead and uncheck user and user history, we'll click Finish.
And now we can take a look at our protein data mapping, and this is not going to be exactly what we want, but
it will generate some of the things that we need here, we've got our user, and our goal, and actually when we
look at this, this is actually pretty close. So there's a couple of things here of course we have our
properties, but then we have our one to one, were basically saying that this maps one to one to user, and
here's the class for user we can go ahead and use this shorter form.
Now we do need to add this constrained, so let's set constrained equal to true, what this is going to do is
it's going to make it so that there has to be exactly one valid user for this property, so it does have to
map, it's going to make sure that it is going to check to make sure that this key is going to match up so
that this protein data will go to a user. So you do want to put constrained in there, then the other thing
that we want to do is we want to set it up so this id is going to be the id of the user.
We're going to use the user id for our id instead of having our own id, so essentially when we look at our
database table it's not going to have a particular protein data id it's just going to reuse the user id.
So if you wanted a query for protein data for a user you just query based on that id.
So in order to do this what we want to do is we don't want to use this assign, were going to go ahead and
have our name, id, our type int, our column name can be id, you could change this to user id if you wanted to.
But then for our generator we actually want to use instead of an assigned were going to use foreign which is
basically meaning it's going to be a foreign key that were going to use for our generator.
And then inside here were going to use this param, and were going to set the name equal to property, and
then user. And so what this is going to do is its basically going to look for the user property on our
protein data and its going to use that as the id so it's going to get the id from there.
And this may look a little bit weird, but this is just the way that it has to mapped in order for this to
work properly, but it's basically just going to grab the data from here, that's why we're saying user
parameter for this param here and using foreign. So now we have our protein data side map, but we have
to make some changes to our user mapping so let's go ahead and go back to that side.
We're going to go to our user, and with user what we want to do is we're going to get rid of this component
since we don't need that anymore, and then on this side were just going to do a one to one, and were going
to name this protein date. And then we need to specify the class, so we're going to set this equal to
com.simpleprogrammer.proteindata. And then we want to set the cascade on this just like we did with the
other one because we want to make sure that when we save a new user we also save the protein data, it
wouldn't real do us much good if we didn't do that. So were going to do Save Update, now we could of course
save each entity by themselves, but that's a big pain when were really using this always from this user
object. So that's pretty much it, the only other thing we need to do is go into our Hibernate config and
we're going to add our mapping, this one is called protein data. So let's go ahead and run this and see what
we get here. So if we look at our console view you can see everything ran correctly and now if we bring up
our SQL workbench, let's go ahead and do a Refresh. You can see now we have this protein data table, we can
select from here and you can see that we have id one, this is going to correspond to the id in the user
table. We've got our total and our goal, so were basically starting protein data in this table.
And if we were to go to our user history, we still have our user history in there its using this user id,
notice it's all one in here. And then if we go to user you'll see that id one and we've got our name value.
So we've basically taken the protein data out of this table, we've moved it into its own table, it has a
matching id that you can use to lookup that data.