Now with the current way we did our one to one mapping
we are using the same id were basically using whatever the users id is for the id for our protein data
table. Now you might not want to do this, you might want to have a separate id for protein data, and
then have the user id reference that as a foreign key. We can change our one to one mapping to do this
pretty easily, all we have to do is go into our mapping file and were going to start with our user mapping,
and what were going to do here is we're going to change this actually from a one to one mapping to a
many to one. So were just going to add a many to one and I'm going to go ahead and copy this to save us a
little bit of time here. Then we'll get rid of our one to one, and lets go ahead and take a look at this
so were setting up a many to one on protein data, we have our class of protein data, we actually gave it a
column name of protein data id, because remember this is going to be the foreign key, the id coming from that
protein data table. We did our cascade save and update, and then we have unique set to true.
So what this is basically going to do is its going to make it so that this is unique, even though this says
a many to one mapping it's going to constrain this with this unique constraint so that in that table this
protein data id has to be unique. So what does that mean? It basically means that were only going to have a
one to one mapping. So even though were using many to one, we end up creating a one to one.
Now on the protein data side we can make a change as well, what we can do here is first of all we don't want
to use the user id we want it to have its own id. So let's change this generator to be in increment, and
get rid of this param part here, and we'll shorten this. So now were just generating an id, and then on
this one to one mapping we can leave this in place, but instead of using constrained true here were actually
going to use this property ref and then were going to say the property that this maps to on the user class,
which is protein data. Now by doing this we'll make sure that this user on our protein data gets populated
with the correct thing here, that it's going to know to look back at protein data and that's how it's going
to determine what the actual user is. So when it looks at that particular user that maps back and it sees
the protein data field that's going to be this particular class. Not completely import ably you understand
exactly how that works, but this is the basic syntax when you want to do this one to one mapping this way.
So if we were to go ahead and run this, and actually before we run this lets make sure we save everything
and we'll go to our program, and let's just go ahead and do something that will just prove that were using
separate id's now. So before we commit this last transaction let's just go ahead and do user.setproteindata,
and we're just going to set a new protein data. So this will give us a new id and we can test this out to
make sure that foreign key is working. So I'm going to go ahead and run this, and we can look at our output,
everything looks good. We're going to go back into our SQL workbench, I'll refresh this.
Now if we look at our protein data, you can see inside here quite a few rows, we have a about four rows in
here. I actually created some fake data ahead of time just to make sure that we'd have unique IDs
that we could test out. So we've actually got four IDs, if we go to our users table and select from here,
you can see that this is actually set to protein data id of four, so the current version of the protein
data for this particular user would actually be this row four with a total 0 and a goal of 0, that one that
we created new. So you can see here the difference really is just that we have on our users this protein
data id, which is a foreign key to protein data. When we had done this the first time they were both using
the same id for the user id.