Another way we can model most of the different relationship types is by using a Join Table.
A Join Table is basically a third table that contains references to both of the tables being mapped, and has
rows that create the mappings between the tables. We can actually model different types of relationships
by putting restriction on the Join Table to make a column or combination of columns unique.
But we'll try to stick to a simple case since Joins Tables can get quite complex.
We can also use a Join Table to include additional information about the mapping, for instance in this
example were mapping a user to a goal alert, which would be an alert that would be triggered when a goal
is met. We could use a user goal alert table to map the user to a specific goal alert, or set of goal alerts
and then the Join Table or sometimes called link table we could have an additional column that has the date
when the connection was added.