So now let's look at an example of using a Join Table or a link table, what were going to do is we're going
to create our goal alert, so I'm just going to create a new class, in fact we should probably switch over to
our Java view to do this, then we'll do a new class and were going to call this goal alert.
And this is just going to represent some alert message that will be given to the user displayed when a
particular goal is met, when they achieve the goal of the number of grams protein that they're supposed to
eat in a particular day. So we'll just create this class and were just going to add to this an id, so we'll
do private int id, and then we'll do a private string message, this will represent the message that's
displayed, and we'll create some getters and setters for this. So now we have our goal alert, let's go ahead
and create our mapping file for our goal alert, were just going to go over to Hibernate view and then go
to goal alert, we'll do new Hibernate XML mapping file, and this should be fine.
And we should be able to actually use this mapping file the only change we'll need to make is on this id
generation, we want to use increment. So now we have our id and our message, real simple mapping.
And really the bulk of the work that we're going to be doing is going to be in the mapping on the user side.
So before we do that though we do need to change our user class, let's make it so we can just have one
optional goal alert. Now you might make a collection of these, you could of course do a one to many, many to
one mapping, many to many, but were just going to keep it really simple here, which will be a one to one
mapping or a one to 0 potentially it will have the option of this not existing.
So were going to do private goal alert, we'll just call this goal alert, and we'll go ahead and create
getters and setters for this. And we're not going to initialize this because this could not exist, we don't
have to have this value. And let's go ahead and do one more thing to make things a little bit simpler in
goal alert lets go ahead and create a constructor, we'll just do this source and were going to say generate
constructor using field, we don't want id we just want message to be passed in so we can create a new goal
alert. And then of course remember we do need to have a parameter list constructor so we'll go ahead and
create that as well. Now we can go into our main program, and let's just go ahead and set up a goal alert.
So we'll do this right here after we've set some of this data on user, let's go ahead and create a new goal
alert, in fact we'll just do user.setgoalalert=newgoalalert and for the message we'll say congratulations.
So now we'll have added this goal alert, we need to set this mapping up and also what were going to do is
on the user side were going to use a join table, so the way that we do this is we use a join here and then
we specify what the table name is and this is going to be user_goalalert because this is going to join the
user table to the goal alert table. Then we want to make this optional so we'll say optional=true because
we don't always have to have an entry in here. And then we need to specify a key, so this is going to be
the key in this column from this table's perspective so from the user table the column we want to have is
called user id, so in this new join table we'll have a user id which will represent this id that comes from
this user that's creating this. And then were going to set up a many to one inside the join table, the join
table is almost like when we embedded the components inside here were basically creating a table inside of
this mapping. So what were going to do with this one is let's make this a shorter version, were going to
give this a name which will be goal alert because this is going to map to that goal alert field on our class.
And then we want to setup the column name so the column for this should be goalalert_id because this is
going to map remember to that goal alert table. Then we want to set up not null because you can't have a
null here if we have an entry in that table it should map to something, and then we'll set our unique equal
to true, this is just going to constrain it so that there has to be only one entry, one alert, since were
doing it this way for now. And then we want to set up our cascade just to simplify things, we'll say cascade
save update, so when we add an entry to this it will automatically create a goal alert, we won't have to save
that entity separately. So now before we run our example let's do one last thing, we need to add this mapping.
So were going to call this goal alert, we'll save this and now we can run our example.
And you can see that everything worked properly we didn't get any errors, we have quite a bit of output here
because we're setting up quite a few different relationships now. So now let's go ahead and look in our
workbench. I'll go ahead and do a refresh, so you can see we have our goal alert table, if I select from here
you can see we have id one, message congratulations, and then let's look at this user goal alert got created.
If we look at this table you can see it has a user id and a goal alert id, they're both set to one, but these
are going to join those two tables together, so goal alert id one basically says okay in the goal alert table
look for id one, this is going to be mapped to in the user table id one.
So if we go to our user table we've got our id one, so this is basically allowing us to map data.
You can imagine how this join table could be used to map different types of relationships from one to many,
many to one, many to many, we can basically use this to map any data from one table from the user id table to
the goal alert table. And we could also add some columns to this, were not going to get into the
complexities of this right now because this can get fairly complex, but I just wanted to show you a basically
of set this up.