So in our example were actually going to make it so that our goal alert can be mapped as many to many
relationships, and we're just going to do a single direction a unidirectional relationship instead of a
bidirectional one just to keep things pretty simple. What were basically going to do is in our user, were
going to make this so that instead of just having a single goal alert were going to have a set of goal
alerts, so we're just going to do set of type goal alert, we'll call this goal alerts.
And we'll set this equal to a new hash set so that we always have at least something we don't have a null
here so we'll say new hash set of goal alert. We'll go ahead and do our imports and then we want to create
some getters and setters for this. And we'll go ahead and remove those old getters and setters from goal
alert. Then in our program let's go ahead and make it so we have a couple of different goal alerts, so were
going to say set goal alerts, and actually what we want to do is we want to get the goal alerts first.
So let's do user.getgoalalerts.add and we'll go ahead and add a new goal alert, so we have one that says
congratulations and let's make another one that says you did it.
Now we'll go into our mapping file, were going to go into our user mapping.
And it's actually pretty easy to set this up we can get rid of this entire join table and we can replace this
with a set, just like we did before. And we'll call this name goal alerts, that's the field that were using
in our user class, and then we want to set the table for this, this will actually be our join table its going
to automatically create this we don't have to use the join syntax here.
So were going to call this user goal alert just like we had called it before. We want to set of course the
cascade option on this to make things easier on ourselves so we'll do save update.
Then inside here we need to specify the key, so the key will be a column called user id.
This will be one of those columns in that table that user goal alert table.
And then were going to use this many to many in order to define the other part of the relationship.
We'll need our class which will be com.simpleprogrammer and then we'll make it .goalalert.
And then were going to say what the column for this one is and this column were going to call goalalert_id.
So that's it we should be able to run our example now, and you can see everything ran correctly without
any errors, we've got quite a bit of data here because it is doing quite a bit now.
And if we go to our SQL workbench lets go ahead and refresh this. We can look at our goal alert we can see
we have id one and two which there are two messages in there. And now if we look at this user goal alert
you can see that user id one has two goal alerts mapped to it, goal alert id one and goal alert id two.
And of course if we look at our users table we can see that we have this user id of one.
So that's a basic unidirectional many to many mapping because we can basically map different number of goal
alerts to a user, and we could also go the other way and we could reuse these goal alerts.
We could have for example in here user id two map to goal alert id one.