The other important concept you should know before we get started, is that of directionality.
This concept is pretty simple; it basically just refers to which direction a relation goes from one piece
of data to another. Relationships can either be unidirectional or bidirectional, a unidirectional
relationship has a reference to one piece of data, but the piece of data reference does not have a reference
back to the other. Consider this example where we have a car that has a unidirectional relationship with
the wheel, the car has a reference to the wheel, but the wheel doesn't have a reference back to the car.
We could set up the relationship to be bidirectional instead where the car would have a reference to the
wheel, and the wheel would have a reference to the car. This is another important thing to take into
consideration when mapping data unidirectional relationships are easier, but sometimes you need to be able
to refer to data in both directions.