I've got our project open and what were going to do is we're basically going to take our user class and were
going to make this into a composite in Java, were basically going to take out this information, the total,
and the goal that applies to the protein part of a user. And were going to put that into another class
called protein data. Then what were going to do is we're going to map this Hibernate to be a component so
that we're going to have this data be in the same table, it's going to be treated as a value type, but its
going to allow us to have that data in separate classes. Now in order to do this all we need to do is
basically start off by creating our new class, so I'm just going to do private, and were going to call this
protein data, and we'll make the variable name be protein data as well, and I'm going to set this equal to
a new instance of protein data. And we don't have a protein data class, so I'm going to go ahead and hit
Control 1 as a shortcut in Eclipse here to do this create class. I'm just going to create this protein
data class, then were going to go back here in user and were basically just going to take total and goal,
we'll cut this, we'll paste it into here, and then we'll take the getters and setters for get total, set
total, get goal, and set goal, then we'll paste that there. Now we have our user class and our user class
is going to have a instance of protein data to hold its protein data, we do need to put some getters and
setters on this, so let's go ahead and create the getter and setter.
And now if we go back to our main program there's a few things that were going to want to do to fix this,
first of all were using this set goal, and get goal, now what we want to do is we want to say get protein
data and then call our set goal, so lets go ahead and fix that everywhere.
(typing)
And let's fix this one, and looks like there's a missing import here, let's go ahead and fix that as well.