Okay so now our mapping isn't quite right, and unfortunately we can't use the tools to do this if we do a
right click here and basically say new Hibernate XML mapping file, and we try to do this for user, you'll
notice when it tries to, it tries to create two files, and if you look at this you can see that it's actually
trying to map these as entities. We can actually go back here and set the depth control to zero, and if we
do that we get something a little closer, but it still is not quite right it still does this many to one, but
what we can do is we can just manually edit this and switch this to be a component.
And the way that we can do this is we can just go inside of here, and were going to add an element called
component. Here we specify the name which is just protein data, and then I'm going to take this end tag for
component and put it here, and then were just going to have some properties inside of this protein data
component. It basically is letting us nest this inside here and its going to flatten everything out, its
just going to use these column names. Now you could give whatever column names you want, this mapping works
just the same as it did with the other columns here in our id. And of course we have some options on
component as well, were not going to get into all of the details of these for the most part you're just going
to put the name there and that going to be the name of the field in your parent class.
So now that we have this mapped lets go ahead and test this out, we'll go back to our main program, I'll
go ahead and run this. Let's take a look at the console, looks like everything is correct here, you can see
that were doing our insert, and then our update, just like we had set up before.
We're going to out SQL, and lets go ahead and refresh this, and I just have a test table here called users 2,
but were interested in this users table. If we take a look at this we can see that we have id, name, total
goal, just like before if I select from here we've got Joe the total of 50, and a goal of 250.
So really our data structure didn't change on the SQL side, but we just changed it on the Java side, and then
by having that mapping and using component we could basically combine two different Java objects.
So you can also use this if you have perhaps a domain model already in your Java application and you would
like to combine things, so you might have broken things up to be very small so that you have very small
defined classes. But you might want all of that data to be in a single table, using components just like
this, you could combine that so you don't have to have mappings, or separate entities for every single
class in your Java application.