Next up the list of difficulty on mapping relationships in Hibernate is mapping valued type collections.
In Java you might have a class that has a collection as a member, for example in our protein tracker app,
as you can see here we could have a user that has a collection of history objects which represents the
history of what has happened to that user. We could represent that history using different types of
collections in Java, we could use a set, a list, a map, or even a generic collection interface, which is
represented in Hibernate as a bag. Regardless of how we represent the data on the Java side, we will need
to create two tables on the relational database side to model this data.
One for the user itself, and then another for the collection of history data.
For each type of collection we can use a special mapping to map the relationship in Hibernate.
Let's take a look at some of the most common collection types and how to map them.