Now let's go ahead and see how we can map some collections in Hibernate, were going to start off with a set.
So let's go into our user, and this time were going to add user history, so what we'll want to do here is
we're going to store this in a set. I'm just going to make a private set of type user history, and we'll
need to create that user history class, and we're going to call this History.
We're going to set the SQL to a new hash set of type user history, and it is very important that when your
using collections and you're going to map them in Hibernate that you use the interface for the type.
You're going to have to have an instance of an actual implementation of course, but here in your actual class
you need to use the interface. Let's go ahead and import these, and the reason why you need to use the
interface is because Hibernate is going to create its own implementation that's basically going to rap
the implementation that you're going to use. So you won't get back a hash set, so this is also important to
know because when you get back your data from Hibernate let's say that you queried your user object and we
got back our history, we couldn't cast this as a hash set, we would want to use this as a set interface,
because it's not going to be this Java hash set, it's going to be a special hash set that Hibernate creates
that is going to be able to track changes to that set. So let's go ahead and do an import on hash set,
and then we'll need to create our user history class, I'll just go ahead and create this class.
And inside this user history class were going to store some information about what's happened, were just
basically going to store the entry time and then an entry. So let's go ahead and make a private date,
called entry time. And then we'll do private string called entry.
And we need to import our date; we want to make sure we use Java util date.
We're going to put some getters and setters. (typing)
And then let's go ahead and construct a constructor that will let us easily create a user history.
So I'm just going to do source and I'm going to generate constructor using fields.
And then remember we need a default constructor, so we're going to create our user history with nothing in it
because Hibernate does need the default constructor to work. Then the last thing were going to do with
this history class is we're going to generate an equals and hash good, that's because with all our collections
Hibernates going to need to build and compare these value types to know if there the same or not.
Because Hibernate is going to need to do some comparisons to see whether or not these things are equal,
because we don't have a unique id for any of these. So the easy way to do this is we can just do source, and
we can just use this generate the hash code in equals. These aren't perfect hash codes and equals, you'll
maybe want to create your own depending on how complicated your type is, but for this simple user history
this should work just fine. So now we have our user history.