Now back in our user class, I'm going to go ahead and create a getter and setter for this history. And let's go ahead and add some history items,
so let's go to our program.Java and let's make it so when we modify some things like setting the goal, lets
after this let's say user get history, and then were going to add history items so we'll say add, we'll do a
new user history, our entry time, we can just do a new date to get the current date time so we'll get our
Java util date. And then for our entry let's say set the goal to 250, and we'll take this same line and
we'll use this in a couple other places. Let's say when we add the protein we'll say added 50 proteins, and
this should be our loaded user. So we'll have a couple items that should get entered into there, and lets go
ahead and add one more for when we set the main, so we can say get history, we can say set name to Joe.
So now that we've loaded up our user lets go ahead and see what's in this set, let's go ahead and make a
loop, were just going to say four and then we'll do user history, and were going to get this from the
loaded user get history. So were going to loop through all of the history items, and then were just going to
print them out, we'll say system.out.printline and were going to print out history.getentrytime.
We'll do a two string on that and then we'll go ahead and put a space and then the actual message, so we'll
do history.getentry.