Hi this is John Sonmez from Pluralsight, and welcome to this last module in the Introduction to Hibernate course.
In this module, we'll be taking a look at some advanced functionality of Hibernate.
We'll be learning about Hibernate features we haven't covered so far
like caching, batch processing, and using interceptors and filters.
We won't be diving too deeply into these topic because this is still and introductory course
but I do think it is important to have at least some knowledge of these topics
even when you're first starting out so that you can know what kinds of features exist
that can solve some pretty difficult problems you may face.
You can always fill in any knowledge in this area later on once you know a little bit about it.
At the end of this module I'll also be recommending an excellent book
which contains more detailed information about Hibernate and expounds upon many of the topics
we'll be covering in this chapter, in depth.