When using Hibernate you may find the need for doing something whenever a save, update,
or other operation happens on an entity in Hibernate.
Hibernate allows you to create interceptors that are basically able to intercept entity operations
like save or update.
And then allow you to execute some code before the operation completes.
One of the most used examples of this is for auditing.
You can use the interceptor capabilities of Hibernate to intercept saves or updates to a particular entity type
and save an audit record to record that change of data.
Interceptors, of course, can be used for other purposes as well.
Let's take a look at an example.