Okay, so we're just going to create a simple interceptor.
This interceptor is basically going to execute whenever we save anything.
So I'm just going to create a new class for this interceptor.
And we're just going to call this AuditInterceptor.
And what we're going to do here is we can either implement the interceptor interface
but it's a little bit easier if we do this extend EmptyInterceptor.
And the reason why I'm going to do this instead of implementing the interface is because
EmptyInterceptor is going to give u some default implementation for everything
so we won't have to implement every single method on the interceptor interface.
Which is quite a few of them and if we don't need behavior for all of those,
we don't need to waste the time trying to implement that when we can just use this EmptyInterceptor.
So the next thing we're going to so is we're just going to go to Source.
And then if you go to Override/Implement Methods you can see all of these methods that we can override.
And this is all the lpaces that we can do something with our interceptors.
We have things like afterTransactionBegin, afterTransactionCompletion, we've got findDirty,
getEntity, instantiate, we're going to just do this save, here.
And then we're also going to do postFlush. Onsave is going to happen whenever we try to save an entity.
PostFlush is going to happen after the data's been actually saved to the database or flushed to the database.
So I'm just going to click OK, and so now we have these autogenerated overrides.
And here we can do whatever we would want to do when this happens.
You can see that we're getting our entity passed in, for example, on this onSave.
So we could do something with that entity, we could basically, get some data out of there if we wanted to,
we could cast this if we knew what the type was.
Perhaps we have some interface that we're using as a marker to determine
whether or not we're supposed to do something.
But in our case, we're going to keep things really simple.
All we're going to do is we're just going to do a System.out.println
and then we're just going to print out Saving and entity.
then we're just going to return false from here.
And we return false because we didn't modify anything in that state variable that was passed in.
If you modify anything with the state then you need to return true.
And then we're going to go ahead and go to our postFlush,
and here let's just go ahead and do a System.out.println,
and we're just going to say After entity has been flushed.
So that's our basic interceptor. Remember you can do whatever you want here.
You can have all kinds of complicated logic to perhaps extract some data from this entity
in order to create a log record that you might save in a database, or something like that.
Often you'll see a pattern where all the saves will get batched up
and then once the flush happens that's when the actually audits will created and sent to the database.
But we're going to keep things very simple, in this case, just to demonstrate this functionality.
So now in order to use our interceptor what we want to do is we're going to set this
at the session factory level.
So we're going to go into our HibernateUtilities and what we're going to do is
on our configuration we can actually set the interceptor.
So before we do this .configure, we're going to do .setInterceptor,
and we're going to set this equal to a new instance of our auditInterceptor.
Now this interceptor is going to be used with everything that gets generated from this session factory.
So if we go ahead and run this code now, you'll notice that our messages are in here.
So, if we look at what's happening, you can see that we have a bunch of saving and entities,
this is where we're generating all that fake data.
So we're doing a lot of saves here.
And then you can see after entity has been flushed, it actually ends up getting called
because we end up doing a flush right here.
And then at the end we do this second query where we're getting Joe, Bob, and Amy,
Remember we're doing that native SQL query, and then the entity becomes flushed again.
So you can see that points where we can use this interceptor.
And if we just look at our code real quick, you can see what's happening here,
when we did our populate sample data we are of course creating our users,
we ended up closing our session, that's where our first flush came from.
And we're saving a lot of data there.
And then when we close our session a second time, that's where that second flush ended up happening.
And I've also found that interceptors can be really useful for debugging.
For instance, you can see that in order to implement this interceptor, to use this interceptor,
all we had to do was add this .seInterceptor to our configuration.
We didn't have to really change any of our code so it's a way to inject some logging
or some kind of debugging into your application because all you have to do is, basically,
do whatever you want to do when a save happens or a flush happens.
And you can either print out messages or you could examine objects and get data.
It gives you some ability to basically, add some functionality at these given points.