Now unfortunately, listeners in Hibernate are not as easy to set up as they used to be.
In Hibernate 4 there was a new way introduced to set up listeners.
So I'm going to show you the new way in Hibernate 4,
and I've actually already set this up because there are quite a few tedious things that we need to do.
But I'm going to explain all of them and then you can practice setting this up
if you want to set up a listener on your own.
So the first thing that we need in order to set up a listener is we need to create a listener.
So I created this LoadEventListener and you can see that this LoadEventListener class
extends a DefaultLoadEventListener.
There is different default listeners for all the types of events,
and in a minute here I'll show you where you can see a list of all the events
and you can get an idea of what you can hook up to.
But basically what I've done here is I've overridden with onLoad
and all I've done here is just -- we're just going to println Entity loaded
and then event.getEntityId. So we'll get the id of that entity.
Nothing really complex here but you can imagine all kinds of use cases where you might want to respond
to an event that happens.
So this is only going to fire whenever we load something in Hibernate.
Now we have our listener class and then the next thing we need to do is we need to inject this into Hibernate.
And so the way that we do this now in Hibernate 4, is we have to have what is basically called an integrator.
Now this integrator needs to integrate this integrator interface.
I created this class called DefaultIntegrator, and when I implemented this integrator interface
it required me to override these particular methods that are in this interface.
The one that's really important is this integrate that takes in a Configuration,
a SessionFactoryImplementor, and then the SessionFactoryServiceRegistry.
Now what we're going to do inside here is we're going to get a chance to do something when Hibernate
is basically it's bootstrapping itself, when it's putting together its configuration.
and we don't have to put this code directly into our Hibernate code.
What I'm mean by this is it's basically going to be autodiscovered if we follow a certain procedure
and convention.
And so we can count on this code being executed when Hibernate starts up.
And inside here what we're doing is we are using this serviceRegistry.
So this is something new for Hibernate 4, this serviceRegistry.
We've seen this a little bit before in out configuration if you remember in our Hibernate Utilities,
I said that we had this service registry builder, we set up our service registry,
and this was another step that we needed for the configuration that's a little bit different
than the previous versions of Hibernate.
So going back to our integrator, let's go into this code, you can see that what I'm doing
is I'm asking the serviceRegistry, hey, give me the service for EventListenerRegistry.
This EventListenerRegistry is basically a service that registers all of these event listeners.
Now it's going to have some default ones, that's how Hibernate actually works,
it's decoupled itself in its architecture so that it has default event listeners
that we going to right things when load happens, for instance.
Then what we're saying is we're going to prepend listeners.
So we want our thing to happen first on to the EventType.LOAD this new LoadEventListener.
And here's a good place to see all of the event types.
If you look at this in numeration, you can see that there's all kinds of events.
AUTO_FLUSH, DELETE, DIRTY_CHECK, EVICT, FLUSH, we've got all these different events that we can hook into.
There's post events and pre events, pretty much everything that goes in Hibernate is available to you
to be able to insert your own code.
So this I really powerful, it's not something that you're going to use everyday
but it is something that is very useful for those times where you need to get in the middle of something
that Hibernate's doing and you need to inject your own mechanism to be able to do something.
So we've got these two pieces and they're joined together but now how do we hook this up to Hibernate?
Well, what we need to do, and I've already set this up, is I've created under the source folder
this META-INF, and then a folder called services,
and then this org.hibernate.integrator.spi.Integrator.
Now this is important that you do this exactly, because Hibernate's going to be looking for this
and if it finds this then it will open up this file and it will look for classes
that will be used for integrators
and you have to give the fully qualified name, one per line,
have to get this exactly right or none of this will work.
It's a little bit of a pain, I'm not completely sure I like the change to this.
It has made things more abstract and looser-coupled but it's made things a little bit more difficult.
So the old way we used to just be able to go into the configuration file and then register a listener from there.
But once you have this all set up then what will happen is that Hibernate will read from here,
find your integrator, it's going to execute code, this integrate.
Which will register our event listener on this load event,
and then whenever we do a load it's going to execute our code.
So let's go ahead and look at our program, I also set up one load here so we can see.
I'm basically loading into our session this user with an id of 1,
and then I'm going to print out the name to verify that we got this particular user.
So we should expect a load to occur there.
Let's go ahead and run this code.
And you can see what's happened, we actually have quite a few entity loads,
you can see that we have when we this SELECT * FROM Users, we got entity loaded 205, entity loaded 205 again,
entity loaded 206, 206, 207, 207, then we went through this particular code and then that last part that I added
we had an entity loaded of 1.
So now you can see with the combination of our listeners and our interceptors we have a lot of power
that older version of Hibernate didn't really allow us to use to be able to get in there and to do stuff.
If you've ever tried to implement an auditing mechanism, or some kind of security within Hibernate,
before using these pieces of functionality, you probably found it pretty difficult to do.
But there's a lot of different things you can do with this
and you just have to make sure that you set this up correctly, follow all of these steps,
everything has to be set up to this exact convention or nothing will work.