Another common problem in many applications using Hibernate is needing to filter data.
For example, I may have certain data that should only be displayed to a user that has a certain role
or security clearance level.
It can be difficult to add this kind of filtering manually to all of the queries
being used to fetch data in Hibernate and is easy to accidently miss one creating a potential security hole.
Hibernate has support for data filters.
Which can defined and attached to a session so that all queries in that session pass through these filters
which filters the data.
Using data filters it is possible to set up filtering logic in a single location
and have that logic applied to all queries executing in a session.