Now in Hibernate, filters are actually pretty easy to configure.
I've already created an example here and we'll walk through this.
What I've done is I've created this filter called nameFilter.
And I've made it so I can pass in a parameter to be able to filter users on a particular name using a like.
So for this example, what I've done is I've said for this session I want to enable this name filter
and I want to set the parameter for name in this filter to be j%.
So basically what this is going to do is it's going to limit any users that are queried
that they're going to have to start with the letter J for their name property.
If they don't, we're not going to see that data.
Now you can imagine how you can apply this to all kinds of other conditions that you might want to have.
Perhaps you had a user access security level, or maybe the date that a user was created,
or some other type of filter that you'd want to apply to all of some set of data.
Now, what I've had to do in order to enable this, is inside user I cerate first of all this filter-def.
And you can define this anywhere under a Hibernate mapping.
It doesn't have to be in user but since this is only going to be used on user
this is a good place to define this.
In this filter-def I give my filter a name, it's called nameFilter.
I set a condition, and this is basically just a where clause
so I'm just using HQL here and I'm just saying where the name is like :name,
remember that's our parameter, and then I'm defining what the parameter is.
There's a parameter called name. It's of type string.
Now I have a filter that I can use with any entity.
Here inside of our user's entity, what I'm going to do is add a filter at the bottom.
You do have to put this near the bottom, you can't put it at the top otherwise you will get an error,
and here I have just set up this filter and I'm saying what the name is, nameFilter.
You can also override the condition here if you want to depending on how you want to use this filter.
But in this case, it's just applying the nameFilter to this user entity.
Now the final step is what we looked a first which is actually inside of our session.
We need to say enableFilter and then say what the filter is, and then any parameters that it needs.
This will make sure that for this entire session this nameFilter will be enabled.
And it's set up to work on user.
So essentially what's going to happen, is this is going to add a where clause or an and, if appropriate,
to the where clause that is going to perform this filter.
And I changed our code a little bit here just to do a regular create query in HQL.
You'll notice if you try to apply this filter with a SQL query, a native SQL query, it won't actually work
because it won't be able to figure out how to append that on.
So this will go through, you have to think about that when you're using filters
another good reason to try to stay with the criteria API and the HQL because if you have a filter
it's not going to get applied to your native SQL.
So we're just selecting all the users here and we're listing the users like we did before.
Let's go ahead and comment out this enableFilter.
And we'll run this and let's look at the output.
So you can see, we have our output that we've been getting before
with our entity loaded, and all of that, and we have Joe, Bob, Amy.
Remember we went through all of our users and then we had gotten Joe by that id of 1.
So everything is working, just as it was before, but now let's see what happens when we enable this filter.
So because we're filtering on name, and we're saying that it's like j%,
we should expect to only get Joe back, ever.
So let's go ahead and run our code now.
And when I go in here in the console you can see what's happened.
We don't have the rest of the users, we just have Joe.
And interestingly, if we look at this select, let's see what we have here,
you can see that it's added something on to the end here.
So you can see right here, we've got his where clause that was just added where user0_.name like ?
and this is going to get filled in with that parameter.
So when you add a filter you're basically just adding a where clause,
so you do have to keep this in mind because if you were to add a filter that would use a join
it's not going to know to join for you automatically.
So you are better off creating a subselect inside of your filter if you need to do a join
than trying to just access some data.
So for example, in our code we created our filter on this property name that exists on user.
If we tried to get the total, if we said proteindata.total, this wouldn't work here, not like this.
We'd have to actually do a subselect here because you couldn't just add this as a where clause
to the end of the query because it requires a join.
So you do have to keep that in mind but filters are pretty easy to define
and they're really useful in the situations where you want to make sure that you're filtering out some data.
If you think about the alternative, if we didn't use this filter what we'd have to do
is we'd have to, in all of our queries, add to the end of this,
this check for a particular user name,
or let's say that we did this for some security mechanism, we'd have to set that.
And the nice thing about this is it's parameterized as well so we could change this filter,
we could make this filter programmatic based on certain conditions.
And this really gives us a lot of ability to make our queries flexible.