Well, we've finally made it to the end of this course.
We've covered quite a bit of ground in this course and hopefully by now you have a pretty good understanding
of what Hibernate is about and how to use it.
We've covered most of the important basic concepts that you'll need to know to maintain an existing
Hibernate application and to even build a new application using Hibernate.
But there's more to Hibernate than what we've covered in this introductory level course.
I usually don't recommend books in my Pluralsight courses,
but I think the 'Java Persistence with Hibernate' book is such a good book that it's worth recommending.
This book covers just about every aspect of Hibernate in detail and it's a great resource for
expanding your knowledge further.
In fact, it's almost 1000 pages so it has a lot of information that we wouldn't be able to cover
even in a very long Hibernate video course.
So if you're interested in learning more about some of the advanced features
of the topics that we covered in this module, this is a great resource.
Do be aware though that some of the Hibernate 4 specific things, specifically around the listeners,
are going to be a little bit different because that has changed in Hibernate 4.
The basics we covered in this course should take you pretty far but you may get to the point
where you really need to dig deep to optimize your queries and troubleshoot difficult problems;
and when you do I'd recommend you take a look at this book.
Well, thanks for joining me on this tour through Hibernate and I wish you well with all your
object relation mapping. Take care.