One of the first optimizations that you may want to do with an application using Hibernate is caching.
Caching itself is not difficult to implement in Hibernate
but using it properly can be a bit of a challenge.
In this section I'm going to show you the very basics of setting up caching in Hibernate
but we won't be going into much of the details of when you should use it
and how best to make use of caching.
First, it's important to understand how caching works in Hibernate.
There are actually two layers of caching.
The first level cache we are already using.
When we work with a session on Hibernate, we don't immediately send SQL statements to the database
after each operation.
Instead the objects we are creating and changing are cached in the first level cache
and all of the changes to the database are persisted at once,
unless we've flushed them earlier.
This first level cache works automatically and saves us round-trips to the database.
But it is important to understand that this first level cache does consume memory.
We'll talk more about this concern when we discuss batch processing.
Next, we have the second level cache.
This level of caching is actually optional and is not turned on by default.
In fact, to use this caching we need to configure it in Hibernate
and use a cache provider to provide and implementation for caching.
The second level cache can be configured to operate at several different levels
but the easiest way to think about it is that it is a cache that exists outside of a single session.
Let's take a look at a very simple example of setting up a basic second level cache.