Now with second level caching in Hibernate, we have to choose a cache implementation,
we don't have one that's automatically included with Hibernate, itself.
We actually have to set up an implementation.
One of the simplest implementations to set up is this Ehcahce.
And if you go to ehcache.org, you can find the download for this and some set up instructions.
We're basically going to be following the set up instructions in here
and we're going to be downloading the latest version on Ehcache.
In order to vet this all we have to do is go to this Documentation.
And then from here, if you go to Hibernate 2nd Level Cache,
you can see there's a Hibernate Table of Contents,
and if you click Hibernate Second-Level Cache,
this has all the instructions and it tells you where you can download the latest version.
What we're going to do to start is just get the latest version of Ehcache.
And you can see that right now there's a 2.6.5.
So I'm going to go ahead and select that version.
And I'm going to go ahead and download this.
And then within here you'll see that there is a .tar,
and we can open with up and then we have the ehcache-core,
inside here what we're really interested in is this lib folder.
This has everything that we're going to need.
So what we're going to do is we're going to copy this over to another temporary location.
I'm just going to go ahead and put this in utilities,
and I'm just going to make under libraries and ehcache,
and here I'll go ahead and put those .jars.
Okay, so now that we have these .jars, what we're going to do is we're going to go over to our project
and we're just going to put this in the lib folder.
We'll need all of these.
So we can just copy them into here.
And then we need to set up our build path.
We're just going to Configure Build Path.
We're going to say add .jars.
And we're going to lib and we're going to select all of these .jars.
So now we're set up to use Ehcache but we still have to configure caching in Hibernate.