So now that we have the latest version of Ehcache, we're going to want to configure this for Hibernate.
And there's a couple things that we're going to want to do.
We're going to need to add a couple of properties to this hibernate.config file.
And then we also need a certain .jar that we're still missing.
So if you go back to where you downloaded this Hibernate release, you're original zip file.
Remember inside here we had gone to this lib directory and we went to required and we got all these .jars.
Well inside here threes also this optional,
and here you can see Ehcache and this actually has all of the Ehcache .jars that you need.
Now I went ahead and showed you how to get Ehcahce from the website
because I want you to know how to get the latest version.
And also so you could have access to that documentation because that's going to be helpful
if you have any trouble with Ehcache.
But you could grab all the .jars here.
The one that we do need, that we're missing though, is this hibernate-ehcache.
So I'm just going to go ahead and copy that directly into our lib folder.
We'll need to extract this out of here first, so I'm just going to paste this
and then I'm going to move this over.
And we can just drop this into our lib folder.
So now we've got our hibernate-ehcache, we'll need to add that to our build path.
So let's go into here and we're just going to go to libraries,
Add JARs and we should find this ehcache.
So now we're set up and we just need to add a couple of properties.
So we're just going to do property, and the first thing we want is hibernate,
and we're looking for cache, and we want region.factory_class.
And I'm just going to use this value that you can find in that Ehcache documentation.
And this value is for Hibernate 4 and greater.
If you're using an earlier version it will be slightly different, this class name.
But for this version it's org.hibernate.cahe.ehcahce.EhCacheRegionFactory.
The older version what net.sf.ehcache.hibernate and then EhCacheRegionFactory.
Then the other property that we need to do is this property to turn on the caching
because by default the second level cache is disabled so we're going to say second_level_cache equals true.
Now we could also set a third property to turn on query caching but we're not going to be covering
query caching in this module but in addition to caching entities we can also cache queries.
Okay, so we don't have any caching set up at this point yet but let's go ahead and test this out
just to make sure that our properties are configured correctly, that we've got all out .jars,
because there are quite a few things that could go wrong.
So I'm just going to run our project.
And we should see it run, just like before, with no problems.
As long as you're getting this output then you're okay.
If you get an error just make sure you have all the .jars that you need,
make sure that these properties are exactly correct because this can be a little bit difficult to troubleshoot.
Most likely you would see an error saying that it couldn't load some class,
which is probably going to indicate that you're missing a .jar.