Now the last thing that you'll need to do is to actually configure some caching strategies for your entities.
And we're not going to go into the details of doing this in this module
because we're going to keep things at a higher level here
and I just want to show you the basic of caching.
You can of course find out more information if you want to actually set up some realistic caching scenarios,
but now you'll know at least how to get started.
So what we're going to do is we're just going to go to our user,
and we're going to add some caching so this could be cached.
So you can just add this cache element here.
And you can see its defaulting to read-only but you have this nonstrict-read-write, read-only,
read-write, and transactional.
And these are going to depend on what cache implementation you're using and how you're using the objects.
We're basically just going to set this to read-write.
Read-only is if you have dadta that doesn't change.
For example, you had a drop down that had a list of states and you're getting that data from the database.
That would be a good candidate for read-only.
Read-write is going to be somewhat flexible because we're going to rarely update this data,
we're mostly going to be reading it if we're using a cache for this, otherwise we really wouldn't need a cache.
So that's going to work for a good majority of your cases.
So we're going to read-write on this.
And then the other thing we're going to so is we're going to go ahead and cache our history
and we're going to do this in two places.
First we have this list, so we're going to add a cache here.
And we're going to make this cache not read-only, we're going to make this one read-write
because we could have new history items created.
But then we're going to go to our UserHistory class, and we're going to add caching here
but we're going to make this one read-only because an individual history item is not going to change.
We don't have any ability to change it.
So now we'll have some very, very basic caching. We can go ahead and run this, test this out.
And we're not really going to be able to very easily prove that we're using the cache, or debug this.
There are of course ways that you can turn on some debugging and logging
and definitely using cache in real application
First of all, you're not going to be want to be implementing caching unless you have a good reason
and you're already checking your performance and you're seeing that caching
is actually improving your performance.
Because believe it or not, caching can actually hurt your performance
if you're making a lot of writes to some objects.
Especially with Hibernate, the way that it's going to have to now go to the secondary level cache
instead of directly going to the primary cache and to the database.
So there is definitely some overhead here.
So you do want to measure things when you're actually using this in a real application
but that's the basics.
Now you can see how to set up caching and that's really some of the harder parts as far as getting started.
Once you actually want to set up your caching, then you'll have to determine what strategy you're going to use
and that's really going to depend on your application and what you're trying to accomplish.
And of course, the performance you're going to have to measure to determine if it's even worth using a cache.