Often times you'll need to make changes to a large number of entities,
with Hibernate, or to insert a large number of entities into your database.
Anytime you're dealing with a large number of entities you should think about how best to handle batching
processing of those entities.
Remember that Hibernate is automatically using a first level cache
so we have to be careful about doing too many operation in a single session
otherwise we could fill up the memory being used by the first level cache.
We have two basic choices for batch processing with Hibernate.
First, we can use HQL queries to actually perform insert, updates, or deletes.
This allows us to change data without having to pull down local instances of all the objects we want to change.
Second, we can periodically flush data from the first level cache to conserve memory.
I'll show you how to do both of these techniques next.