Now the first way that we can do a batch processing type of operation with Hibernate
is to just use HQL and do an update, an insert, or a delete statement.
So let's go ahead and do a very simple update here first.
I'm just going to put this query at the end of our code here.
So we're just going to say query equals session.createQuery,
and lets' imagine that we want to reset all of the users' proteinData.
So we want to set all the proteinData total equal to zero.
This is something that we'd likely want to do in our application.
Now, it doesn't seem like a big deal to go ahead and get all the users and then reset their proteinData.
But let's suppose that we had thousands of users in the system, or maybe even, hundreds of thousands of users.
We wouldn't want to pull down all that data, then make changes, and then do updates.
It makes more sense to just do the updates right on the database.
And so that's good reason to do a batch update using this HQL update.
So the way that we can do this is we can just do update
and then we're just going to say ProteinData, we'll call this pd,
and we're just going to do a set pd.total equal to zero.
Now if we had parameters in here we could set those parameters just like we did on our queries before.
And then let's go ahead and do our import to make sure we have our query.
Now to execute this we can just call execute update.
So we're just going to say executeUpdate, and that should do our update.
So let's go ahead and run this code.
And you can see that we get this Hibernate: update protein_tracker.PROTEINDATA set TOTAL = 0
because that's that it actually did and if we were to look at the workbench,
and we actually go into our protein_tracker database.
If we look at this proteindata table,
we'll select all from here and you can see that all the totals are set to zero.
Everything has been blanked out to zero and that's because we did that update.
We can do the same thing with Goal just to prove that this is working.
So let's say we set all the goals to zero.
We can run this, and now all the goals will be set to zero.
Go back over here, and we can check this by running this query and you can see everything is set to zero.