Hi this is John Sonmez from Pluralsight and welcome to this course on Hibernate.
Hibernate is one of the most well-known object relational mappers or ORM's in the Java world and shaped
much of the way other ORM's were built in both Java and other environments, but Hibernate can be a bit
tricky to get started with. Unfortunately there isn't a quick way to just get going with Hibernate,
because Hibernate although powerful is a fairly complex framework.
This course aims at making it as easy as possible to understand enough of the basics of Hibernate to get
started with it. In this course I'll take you through the process of getting Hibernate set up, which can
be one of the most difficult parts of working with Hibernate, and I'll show you everything you need to know
to be able to map your Java classes to SQL tables, and use Hibernates powerful query language to query
your database. By the end of this course you should be able to set up Hibernate to work with a Java
application and know how to use the basic features of Hibernate as well as some of the advanced ones.