So now let's go ahead and get our Java project created. Now I'm going to be using eclipse during this
course, but you can use IntelliJ, or NetBeans, or whatever IDE that you would like.
The reason why I'm using eclipse is because it is free and the free version of eclipse does have a Hibernate
plugin, which I'm going to show you in a minute. Now you can use IntelliJ, and IntelliJ does have Hibernate
support, but only for the paid version. So if you do have the paid version and you do like IntelliJ you can
go ahead and do that. Most of what were going to cover is going to apply the same to IntelliJ as well as
Eclipse of any IDE because we're not really going to be doing IDE specific things, instead were going to
be creating configuration files, and really the plug-ins just help us to do that.
So let's go ahead and first within Eclipse setup our Hibernate plug-ins.
So if you go to Help and then install new software, what you'll want to do is go to available software sites,
and then you'll want to add, you can see that I've added this JBoss tools core.
So let me go ahead and edit this, and you can see this link here, http download.jboss.org/jbosstools updates
stable juno. And this is because I'm using thee Juno version of Eclipse.
And if you want to find this instead of copying this link, if you just search for Hibernate tools eclipse,
it should pretty much take you to this Hibernate tools page.
And then here you can see it has the Hibernate tools for Eclipse and Ant.
And form here if you click on Downloads you can see that there are the update sites that are listed here.
So in our case, I'm using Eclipse 4.2.2, if you have an older version of eclipse you might want to pick one
of these other ones. But I would encourage you to update to the current version of Eclipse so that you can
follow along exactly in this course. And you can go to the Stable release, and if you click this you'll
notice it gives you some steps. Basically it's telling you to take this link and copy this into here.
So if you do that then what you can do is click OK, and then you'll wan to select to work with this JBoss
tools core, and you can see this gives you all the tools. You'll want to narrow this down to Hibernate,
so if you just do a search on Hibernate, you can see that there's Hibernate tools and JBoss Maven Hibernate
configurator. All we really need is to Hibernate tools, so you can check this one.
You can go ahead and install this JBoss Maven Hibernate Configurator if you want to use Maven as well.
And you can see they're listed under a few different categories, so there all the same thing you only really
need to select these two. And then just click Next, and install this.
I already have this installed, and when you have this installed you should be able to see this if you click
on already installed, and should show Hibernate tools here. And then it will ask you to restart Eclipse.
And really what this is going to do for us, is its going to give us some tooling to be able to make it
easier for us to use Hibernate configuration files and to create them, and it will give us a perspective
that we can launch that will let us view things from a Hibernate perspective.