So the next thing were going to want to do is to get Hibernate in our application, so I'm going to go ahead
and create a lib folder, we just go to New folder, were going to call it lib, and we'll put all our libraries
in here. So let's go ahead and find our Hibernate libraries, were going to get all these jar files, I'm
just going to Copy them right here. So now we have all those and then there is one other thing we'll need
which is, I'm going to go to the default place where My SQL installed the My SQL connector, basically the
Java connector to the JDBC driver, so it's under program files x86, and then under My SQL.
There is a connector J, this is what we're looking for, and you can see that there's this My SQL
connector-Java and this jar file we can basically copy into the lib folder as well.
Now just because these are in the lib folder doesn't mean there accessible, so what we have to do now is go
to our build path, were going to say configure build path. We're going to go to libraries, were going to
do this add jars, and were basically going to add everything inside of our lib folder.
Then we'll click OK, now you can see these are showing up as reference libraries.
Now we're all set to create a Hibernates configuration to actually be able to use Hibernate.