Now in order to be able to use Hibernate, like we said before we need to have a Hibernate configuration
file, which is an XML file, you can also do it as a properties file, or you can do it programmatically.
In most cases most developers will use an XML file, because that's the most flexible and it's very
descriptive. So were going to go ahead and use an XML file, were going to change our perspective now to
this Hibernate perspective. And now you can see that there's this Hibernate section over here, and this
actually has some interesting things that we'll take a little bit of a look at later, were not going to
focus too much on this since were more concerned with Hibernate itself and not the Eclipse plug-in.
But there is an HQL editor for the Hibernate query language as well as a criteria editor which can be very
useful. What were going to do though is we're going to click on this Add Configuration, and from here were
going to set up our configuration. We're going to set our Hibernate version to four, were going to choose
our project which is protein tracker. And then for our data base connection were going to say Hibernate
configured connection, we could have also said JPA, but remember were going to be doing things the Hibernate
way. Now I said we could use a property file or a configuration file, were going to go ahead and use the
configuration file, so we'll need to create a new config.xml. So let's go ahead and say Create New.
And then we'll click Next, and we'll need to fill our this configuration file, so we're going to go ahead and
leave the session factoring name blank for now, were going to choose our database dialect, which is going
to be My SQL, were just going to do the generic My SQL one. For our driver class were going to use this
com.MySQL.JDBCdriver. Our connection URL is basically going to be our host name and then our port, so what
we're going to do here is we're just going to put local host, and then 3306.
And were going to need to specify a default schema to use, so we're going to flip over to My SQL real quick
and create a database for our application. So I'm going to go ahead and run My SQL workbench if you just
search for My SQL under Start or under your programs, you should find My SQL workbench.
And we're going to go to our local instance, and we need to put in our route password.
And then you can see that we already have some databases here some schemas basically that will hold our
information, but were going to go ahead and create a new schema, so I'm just going to go ahead and click here
to create a new scheme. We're going to call this one protein_tracker, were going to leave everything default.
And we'll click Apply, and Finish. So now we have this protein tracker schema, we don't have any tables or
anything in here, but that fine for now. So now we can go back over here, and for default schema were going
to have protein_tracker, we won't have a default catalogue, we have a user name which is appuser, remember
our password is appuser as well. I'm going to click Finish, so now we have our main configuration file.
I'm going to go ahead and click Apply, and then OK. And we'll minimize this over here so we can see just a
little bit better. What we're looking at now is this Hibernate.cfg.xml file.
Now you could manually create this, but we sped things up a little bit by using these eclipse tools, if
you look at the source this is basically what we have is all of this configuration set up as properties for
our session factory. And part of the nice thing about using these tools in eclipses plug-in is that we can
just go here to session factory and we can modify a lot of these things directly inside of here.
We can put stuff for Hibernate, for example we want to set the show SQL to true, because this will make it
so we can see our SQL that's being generated, which will help us when we're learning about Hibernate, its
useful to see what SQL is actually being generated. There's a bunch of different options here that you
can take a look at, but for the most part were going to be fine with what we have for now.
When we create our mapping file, we'll actually add the mapping here because Hibernate needs to know where
each mapping file is. But for now this should work, the next thing that were going to do is to basically
test out this configuration by trying to create an instance of our session factory.