Now typically in an application that uses Hibernate, what we want to do is we want to have a session factory
that we can access from anywhere because we need to get our sessions from our session factory.
Remember that were going to do everything that we do in Hibernate through he use of our session, then
we'll be creating a transaction in that session. But in order to do that it makes sense usually to go ahead
and create a singleton that has the session factory, or instance of it that we can get from anywhere in the
application. So were going to go ahead and do that next, now before we do that lets go ahead and fix
this so that we have a name space, so were not using the default.
I'm just going to create a namespace called com.simpleprogrammer. And I'm going to move our program under
there. Next let's go ahead and create a new class, and I'm just going to call this Hibernate utilities.
I'm going to put our utilities inside of here that we need to access from anywhere.
And inside this class, what were going to do is we're basically going to create our session factory and
make it accessible. So let's do a private static session factory, and we'll call this session factory.
And I hit Control Shift O there to do that auto import if you're not familiar with Eclipse.
And then we need to have a service registry, and if you have worked with Hibernate before and you haven't
worked with the newer version 4.0, you'll probably not be familiar with service registry.
Service registry is something new that's been added, and it's really not going to affect us much, its
basically just adding another layer of abstraction here to enable Hibernate 4.0 to work slightly differently,
but for everything that were doing it's not going to matter, because in the end all were trying to do is
get a session factory. So were going to pretty much ignore the difference there, and you'll see how we do
this slightly differently than an initialization that you might be used to for Hibernate.
So were going to create a static block, and were going to put a try block in here, and the first thing
we need to do is get our configuration, so let's create a configuration.
And were going to set the SQL to new configuration, and we'll go ahead and import this.
We want to use the Hibernate configuration, and then we need to actually call configure on this, and what
will happen is when we create this configuration and we call configure, it's going to automatically find
this Hibernate.cfg.xml file, it's going to use the configuration that we specified in there so it will know
where the JDBC driver is, the dialect to speak, all of that information.
So once we have our configuration we need to get our service registry, and we get this by doing service
registry=new, and were going to use a service registry builder, and were going to call on this apply settings
plural. And here we need to pass in configuration.getproperties.
This is going to be the properties for our configuration, and that is basically going to allow us to
configure this service registry, and then once we have our builder we want to actually build this, so
we're going to say build service registry. All this does is get us our service registry, again it's not
important to understand exactly what this does, but we need a service registry in Hibernate 4 in order to
get our session factory, which is what were really after. So now that we have that lets set our session
factory equal to congfiguration.buildsessoinfactory and were going to use this one that takes a service
registry. Now we have our session factory, were going to put a catch block here just in case we have a
problem. And were going to catch Hibernate exception, we'll call this exception.
And if we have a problem let's just do a system.out.printline problem creating session factory.
Just so we know if there's an issue and we don't try to go on past this.
Then the next thing that we want to do is we want to just create a public static method called, Get session
factory, they'll return us our session factory and we'll just make this return that instance we have.
So were just going t o say return session factory. And that's it, now we can use this to get our session
factory, quite a bit of code here just to get started, a lot of setup for Hibernate.
But once you get this setup then you'll be good to go, you just have to walk through these steps and get
everything setup. Unfortunately there is not just an easy way to turn on Hibernate and get going.