So now were actually ready to test out our setup, we can't actually store any data yet, because we still have
to credit mapping. So there's still even more configuration, but we can at least test this out to make sure
that were able to hit the database and everything is working. So before we do that I'm going to go into our
Hibernate config, and for the session factory the tools are a little bit older than the newer version of
Hibernate, so right now there generating a couple of things that are a little bit dated.
First of all it's adding this name equals, when you don't specify a name for a session factory, and this
can cause an error. And second of all in the dtd's it actually specifies Hibernate.sourceforge.net
You'll see a warning that comes up because this has changed, but we can leave that, that one's not a big deal.
We do have to change this so, because you will have a problem if you don't.
So what were basically going to do is we're just going to try to create a session, open a new session, and
close it. And if we can do that, then we can be pretty sure that we configured everything correctly and were
able to access our database. So what were going to do is do Hibernate utilities.getsesionfactory and then
we're just going to say Open Session. That will give us a new session, we'll store this in a variable called
session. We'll need to import session, and then were just going to say session.close and that's pretty much
it. So let's go ahead and run this, and we can look at the output here, let's go ahead and make this big.
So we got Hello world, and then if you look through here most of these are info, so we can see some of the
things that loaded up. Anything that's info we don't really have to worry about, we do have a warn here,
and remember this is that obsolete name space, so it tell us that we should be using Hibernate.org.
You can change that if you want to, but it's not really important, and then we can see that session factor
was configured, some additional information here, everything looks right saying what driver it's using,
it's connecting to local hosts, and it's using this connection property for our app user, and our password,
set up our dialect, everything looks like it's working properly. So all signs point to that we have
everything configured correctly, and working. Now if you see an exception here, or some errors, you may
have something configured incorrectly you might have to go back through and make sure you have everything
exact. I know this is fairly tedious, but I promise you that once you have everything working and
configured, you won't have to go through this again, at least for a simple project.
So it's important to get the setup the right way the first time, take your time, don't worry that this is
taking a long time at first. It's a little bit intimidating, but once you get the setup then things will
be much faster and once easier inside of Hibernate.