This course is designed for developers that want to learn the basics of Hibernate, to be able to use it for
persisting Java objects in a SQL database. So in order to get the most out of this course you'll need to at
least be somewhat familiar with Java, you don't have to be an expert, but you will need to know the basics
in order to understand hibernate since we'll be writing Java code to use Hibernate.
It will also help greatly if you have some knowledge of SQL in relational databases since Hibernate maps
Java objects to relational database tables. It is possible to use Hibernate without understanding much
about relational databases, but if you ever need to troubleshoot a Hibernate query, which is more of a when
then and if, you'll definitely want to understand how the SQL that Hibernate is generating works.
So if your uncomfortable with SQL I'd recommend you take one of the SQL courses first and then come back
here. In this course we'll be sticking mostly to the basics, but we'll also cover some of the advanced
features in the last module, so even if you already know something about Hibernate you'll probably find this
course to be useful for filling in gaps in your knowledge. If you're already an expert in Hibernate though
you'll probably find this course to be pretty boring.