This course will take you through the process of setting up Hibernate, mapping objects to relational tables,
and querying those objects using Hibernates query language. We'll start out with the module your currently
watching where we'll learn a bit about what an ORM is and what Hibernate does, and get it set up with my
SQL as our database, as well as learn how to setup the Hibernate configuration.
Then in Module 2 we'll learn about one of the key parts of Hibernate, mapping files.
We'll learn the basics of creating a map and file that maps a Java class to a SQL table.
And we'll learn how to do some basic storing and retrieving of data using our mapping files.
In module 3 we'll continue our education about mapping and Hibernate as we learn how to model relationships
between objects and relational tables in our mapping files. We'll learn how to map different kinds of
relationships, like one to one and one to many, and get into some of the complexities of mapping files.
Then in Module 4 we'll learn all about querying using Hibernate, we'll learn the basics of using the
Hibernate query language to query objects stored in the database, and see how to use the criteria API's
to create complex query's. Finally in the last module we'll take a brief look at some advanced topics,
like cashing, transactions, and interceptors. We won't be going in depth into any of those subjects, but
we'll be learning enough about them to understand the basics and when they should be used.