Before we can really use Hibernate we need to understand the foundation on which it is built.
Hibernate is a persistence technology that is based on the idea of object relational mapping or ORM.
In ORM is a framework that enables you to map the world of objects found in object oriented languages like
Java to rows in relational tables found in relational databases like My SQL.
To understand this concept better let's look at an example, here you can see that I have a table called
Persons, that contains columns with each piece of data associated with an individual person.
We have a column for an Id which uniquely identifies each person.
A column for the person's name, another column for their age, and finally a column that has an addressedId,
which refers to an Id in an address stable where information about their address is stored.
The addresses table has its own set of data that you can see here. If we wanted to write some Java code to
store a new person in the tables, it isn't so easy. Perhaps we have a person object in Java, like you can
see here that has fields for the Id, name, and age, and also contains a reference to another Java object
that has there address data. Without an ORM we have to translate this object into a few different SQL
statements that will insert the person data into the person table, and insert the address data into the
address table, then update the persons tables address Id with the Id that was created in the address table,
or we could do it the other way around, but either way we'd have to do several inserts in order to insert
this data. Writing Java code to create the SQL to do this isn't that hard, but it is a bit tedious and
pretty easy to get wrong. That's where an ORM comes in; using an ORM like Hibernate we can declare how
certain Java classes should be mapped to relational tables and let the ORM deal with the nasty job of
creating the SQL to insert, update, delete, in query data in our persons and addresses tables.
This allows us to keep our Java code focused on using objects and have those objects automatically translated
to the realm of relational tables. So really what an ORM does is it saves us from manually having to map
objects to tables.