Hibernate is just and open source ORM that is able to map Java objects to a variety of different relational
databases. Hibernate is a framework that allows us to specify the configuration to use, to connect with our
database, and to specify the way which our Java object should be mapped to relational tables.
And it does a job of creating SQL that is able to Save, Update, Delete, and query data from the database.
It presents this data to us as Java objects that we can use and manipulate then save back to the database.
Hibernate has a pretty long history as it was originally created in 2001 by Gavin King and was originally
designed to be a better alternative to the current persistence in Java offered by EJB2 style entity beans.
Don't worry if you don't know what those are you probably don't want to know.
Those were painful times indeed. And Hibernate is still under development as at the time of the recording of
this course, Hibernate 5.0 is being developed with a goal of having JPA 2.1 support, which we'll talk about
next.