Before we move on and talk more about Hibernates architecture, I want to briefly talk about how Hibernate
relates to JPA. JPA stands for the Java persistence API, and it is a specification of a common persistence
API for Java. JPA itself is not a framework, but a specification that a framework can implement to be
considered JPA compatible. You can think of JPA like a Java interface, and Hibernate like a class that
implements that interface. So what then is the purpose of JPA? Well JPA is an abstraction layer over a
specific implementation of persistence in Java so it allows you to write Java code that uses JPA interfaces,
which can work with any persistence framework that implements the JPA spec.
In other words if you write an application using only JPA interfaces for your persistence you could swap out
Hibernate at some point with another ORM theoretically without changing any code.
Now this is great if you're planning on switching out your ORM framework, or you need this kind of flexibility.
But in practice I found that most software projects rarely try to switch out an ORM or even the underlying
database technology. So there are two reasons why in this course we'll be covering using Hibernate through
Hibernate API's instead of JPA API's. First as you can see in this diagram, Hibernate is more than just
JPA. There are plenty of non JPA things in hibernate, which are quite useful.
Unless you have a really good reason to limit yourself to just what JPA can do, I don't see the point in
restricting yourself to just JPA. We might as well use the Hibernate API and get the full power of
Hibernate. Second since this course is about Hibernate and not about JPA, it makes more practical sense to
cover Hibernate since if you're using JPA it doesn't matter what underlying technology your using, once you
know how to get it setup. Don't worry though if you want to use JPA in your application, you'll find that
a great deal of how JPA works and even the API is very similar to Hibernate anyway, since JPA was heavily
influenced by Hibernate.