So were going to start off by setting up our environment, and the first thing we are going to do to setup
our environment is to get our relational database. In this course were going to be using My SQL as our
relational database, and that's because it's a fairly robust database, and it is also free, at least there is
a free version of it. And you can of course use whatever database that you want, you're just going to have
to make a few different changes in the configuration, but if you want to follow along here, you can go ahead
and get My SQL and you'll want to go to MySQL.COM from here you'll click products.
It can be a little bit confusing to navigate around here because of the different My SQL additions, but what
we want is the free community edition, so if we go to this download my SQL community server link.
Then here we can find the general availability releases and you can choose whatever operating system your
using, in this case I'm using Microsoft Windows. And there is actually a My SQL installer MSI file that
makes it really easy to install.
So I'm just going to go ahead and download this, and you can see that it gives me two choices, either a web
based installer, or the full installer. I'm just going to go ahead and choose the web based one, and you
don't actually have to sign up here, it looks like you do, but this is just a little trick to try and get you
to sign up, but you can just click this No thanks just start my download link.
And when you do that it will go ahead and start this MSI, which we can run.
Then you should see this Welcome screen, where we can click Install My SQL products.
We need to Accept the license, click Next, and I'm going to go ahead and let this do a check to find the
latest products, which we already had the latest so there shouldn't be any problem.
Then we'll click Next, and I'm just going to choose the developer default, if you want to if you understand
a little bit more about My SQL you can choose one of these other ones, either do a full or custom, but
developer default will work for most people. So were going to click Next, and then you'll see what the
requirements are, and these are the requirements based on that default developer profile.
So you'll see some things like the Visual studio in Microsoft, .NET, if you don't have these things, so
if you're missing some of these requirements and you do want to still install this, you can go back here and
go to custom, and then from here you can go ahead and pull out the different things that you don't want.
But you might as well just do the developer default unless you have a problem, because you're going to get
everything you need. So I'm going to go ahead and click Execute, and one more time on the Execute.
You can see its installing the Python connectors that it needs.
So all the prerequisites are met, now I'm going to click Next, and now it's going to basically download each
one of these components and install them. And just too briefly go over some of these, we have the My SQL
server, this is our main database engine. We have this workbench, which is a very nice tool for interacting
with My SQL, it makes it easy for you to run queries, and to see the database without having to do everything
from the command line. We've got a notifier, which isn't that important, some excel connectivity, this
connector J, which basically has our JDBC driver and then the .NET driver as well, our documentation and
then some samples. So let's go ahead and click Execute, and you can see its going to download all this, and
install it, and I'll go ahead and let this happen and then we'll resume from here.
So you can see everything is installed now, I'm just going to go ahead and click Next.
And then we need to configure My SQL, the actual server part, so we're going to click Next.
The config type we can choose what our config type is, in most cases were just going to want this development
machine. The default port is 3306, and by default it will open the firewall so that you can access this from
the network. I'm just going to leave this as a default; I'm not going to select this show advanced options.
Now we need to set a route password because all My SQL databases need to have a route user, which is
basically the admin user, or the user that can access everything in the database.
So I'm just going to set for the route password, Password. Obviously you don't want to do this if your
storing any sensitive data in your database, but I'm just going to keep things pretty simple.
You can also add a user account here, let's go ahead and add one called appuser.
And we can put this on all hosts or local hosts, it doesn't really matter, the role were going to leave this
as DB Admin so that they'll have basically full rights to the database.
Authentication will be My SQL and I'm going to make this password, Appuser.
Again you probably want to use a more secure password for your database.
Now we're going to click Next, and then we can basically set this to run as a Windows service, and start it
at system startup. If you do install just remember that you have this running when you're done with My SQL,
you might not want to always have this running as a service. If you don't choose to install this as a
Windows service, you can always start the service yourself, or if you don't choose to start the My SQL server
at system startup you can go into services and start that, it's up to you.
I'm going to go ahead and leave this as default, and also leave this as a default to Standard System Account
for running it. And we'll click Next, it's going to configure the product, and we'll click Next again.
And Next one more time, and then we can start the My SQL workbench right afterwards, and you can see that
this brings up this My SQL workbench which has a lot of different tools in here for administrating your
server, for doing some data modeling, and for doing SQL development.
This is probably the most common thing that you'll use, which if we just double click this we are asked for
our route password, and if we enter that then it takes us into a window here where we can see a couple of
databases, that are already populated with some data, and we can go ahead and run queries against these.
For example I could do a Select star from city, and run this and I'm getting all of the data form that
particular database. So this is a pretty useful tool if you want to use My SQL.
We're not going to get to much into this as were going to be mostly interested in just using My SQL for
Hibernate, but now you should have My SQL installed and we are ready to get started with a Java project and
actually get Hibernate.