Now the next thing that we need is Hibernate, were just going to download Hibernate for now, and then when we
create our Java project were going to add the Hibernate jars to it.
So what you could to is just go to www.hibernate.org, then go to downloads, and then from here there's
actually a few different options that you have. You can see that at the time of recording this course the
current final released version of Hibernate is 4.2.3. And just to let you know the documentation for
Hibernate really is still a little bit dated, at least at the time of recording this course, so some of the
new 4.0 type of things are not in the documentation it's still really treats it as if it were Hibernate 3.
So if you are looking at the documentation and you do get confused just be aware that it may not be fully
up to date. Now the way that were going to use Hibernate is were actually going to download this
Final.ZIPP, I'm going to go ahead and start this download, and I'm just going to go ahead and click this
direct link. And it's a pretty big download, 64.5 megabytes, and that's because it contains all the source
code and everything. And the reason why were going to do it this way is because this will simplify things a
little bit, were just going to basically get the jars out of the lib folder here.
You could of course use Maven if you're familiar with Maven, if we go back to that page here you can see
that it has some information about the Maven repository artifacts.
Or you can use Ivy or something like that, if you're familiar with that.
But we're going to keep things simple and basically just copy the jars into our project once we've downloaded
Hibernate. Alright so now that we've got the Hibernate file downloaded, let's go ahead and take a look
what's in here, so you can see that we have this Hibernate release 4.2.3 final.
And we actually have everything in here if you wanted to actually build Hibernate yourself, which is sort of
nice because if you had some problem and you need to debug it you do have the source code.
But we won't be doing any of that in this course, instead were going to be interested in this lib folder.
And what were going to look at is this required, into here is everything that were going to need.
So what I'm actually going to do is I'm going to copy this over on my machine I have the utilities directory,
under here I have libraries, and I'm just going to put Hibernate in here and then paste all of these jars
over. And we'll come back to this when we actually set up our project we'll be adding all these jars to
our project. So now that we have Hibernate, we can go ahead and create our Java project, we can use these
jars so we can get Hibernate configured to communicate with My SQL.
And the only other missing piece is we'll need to have the JDBC driver from My SQL.